340: 
341: \section{Operational interface}
342: 
343: For this long technical supplement and its two-page CICM presentation artifact,
344: the following finite interface is sufficient.
345: 
346: \begin{definition}[Operational acceptance interface]
347: \label{def:operational-acceptance-interface}
348: A \emph{claim} is a manuscript assertion that can affect a mathematical,
349: artifact, route, or submission decision.  A \emph{load-bearing claim} is a claim
350: whose removal would change a theorem statement, a case-study conclusion, or the
351: submission-readiness status.  An \emph{advisory output} is any AI-agent draft,
352: score, suggested theorem, review packet, or repair proposal before a gate records
353: it.  A \emph{deterministic gate} is a repeatable predicate, script, or checklist
354: whose inputs and pass/fail decision are recorded independently of the prose
355: generated by an agent.  A \emph{human promotion} is the explicit editorial act
356: that moves a candidate into publication state, for example by creating an active
357: \texttt{2026\_*} paper directory with \texttt{main.tex} and \texttt{PIPELINE.md}.
358: An \emph{evidence surface} is the set of source paths, commits, commands, logs,
359: inventories, and witness records cited for a claim.  An \emph{acceptance entry}
360: is a manuscript or submission-ledger record that marks a candidate claim as
361: usable in the publication-facing argument.  \emph{Accepted work} is the subset of
362: candidate claims with such an entry.  This is a status notion only: the
363: definition records that an editorial acceptance entry exists, but it does not by
364: itself assert external editorial acceptance or that the entry is gate-sound.  A
365: pipeline is \emph{gate-sound for acceptance} when each acceptance entry records
366: the claim kind, the evidence surface, the evidence level, and a pass record for
367: every gate in $\Gamma$ assigned to that claim kind, and when a route-boundary
368: entry also records human promotion.
369: 
370: The deterministic dispatch function $\Gamma$ from claim kinds to gates is part
371: of the operational interface.  Its domain is
372: \[
373: \{\text{formal-source},\text{ traceability},\text{ route},
374: \text{ submission},\text{ artifact},\text{ discovery},\text{ work-selection}\}.
375: \]
376: It sends formal-source claims to the build and axiom-purity gates; traceability
377: claims to inventory and marker-existence gates; route claims to promotion,
378: overlap, and submission-state gates; submission claims to submission-pack gates;
379: artifact claims to status and limitation-ledger gates; discovery claims to the
380: pinned discovery gate above and, for extension claims, to the theorem-content
381: delta gate; and work-selection claims to the scheduler gate, whose evidence
382: surface is a critical-path score or backlog window together with the claim kind
383: that the selected item is meant to advance.  For mixed claims, $\Gamma$ returns
384: the union of the gate sets for the claim kinds present.
385: 
386: The route gates have separate operational meanings.  The \emph{promotion gate}
387: uses the active-paper evidence surface, namely a human promotion act producing a
388: \path{2026_*} directory with \path{main.tex} and \path{PIPELINE.md}; passing
389: means the candidate may be daemon-visible publication work, and failing means it
390: remains intake or source material.  The \emph{overlap gate} uses route identity,
391: semantic-overlap ledgers, submitted-sibling paths, and program-board state;
392: passing means advancement is route-disjoint or has a recorded resolution, and
393: failing means advancement is blocked until closure, merge, supersession, or
394: waiting for prior feedback.  The \emph{submission-state gate} uses submission
395: markers, venue state, board state, and submission-pack metadata; passing means
396: the route's publication state permits the proposed action, and failing means the
397: action would duplicate, race, or under-specify an active or submitted route.  The
398: \emph{theorem-content delta gate} uses theorem inventories, hard-lint output, and
399: delta records such as \path{ARTIFACT_INVENTORY.md}; passing means that an
400: extension claim identifies load-bearing mathematical content, and failing means
401: that compilation, file churn, or surface edits may not be reported as substantive
402: theorem growth.
403: 
404: A \emph{reviewable artifact} for this paper is either a public repository file,
405: a supplemental file included with the submission, or an explicit
406: historical-evidence boundary stating that the local path is used only as
407: path-verified evidence and not as a fresh command-run claim.  A \emph{case
408: witness record} is path-complete when its evidence surface gives a
409: concrete source or artifact path for each load-bearing component of the row.  A
410: route-overlap witness has the fields \emph{route identity}, \emph{submitted
411: sibling}, \emph{overlap reason}, \emph{gate decision}, and \emph{allowed next
412: actions}.  An artifact-limitation witness has the fields \emph{artifact status
413: path}, \emph{limitation ledger path}, \emph{observed limitation}, \emph{gate
414: decision}, and \emph{allowed manuscript claim}.  A promotion witness has the
415: fields \emph{candidate surface}, \emph{human promotion evidence},
416: \emph{active-paper markers}, \emph{gate decision}, and \emph{allowed manuscript
417: claim}.  A theorem-content witness has the fields \emph{changed surface},
418: \emph{theorem inventory or hard-lint surface}, \emph{substantive-content delta},
419: \emph{gate decision}, and \emph{allowed manuscript claim}.  The inventory files
420: \path{ARTIFACT_INVENTORY.md}, \path{SOURCE_MAP.md}, and
421: \path{review_bundle/REVIEW_BUNDLE_MANIFEST.json} are part of the evidence surface
422: for this paper and give the compact path catalogue used by
423: Table~\ref{tab:case-witnesses}.
424: 
425: We distinguish two evidence levels.  A claim is \emph{path-verified} when this
426: paper records the relevant source path, artifact path, pinned commit or local
427: publication path, and gate decision, but does not assert that a command was
428: freshly rerun for this submission.  A claim is \emph{command-run} when the paper
429: also records the command, source commit, environment, exit code, and log path
430: for a fresh run.  This long technical supplement uses path-verified architecture
431: and case evidence unless explicitly marked command-run.
432: 
433: A uniform \emph{pass record} is the finite tuple
434: \[
435: \rho=(g,I,d,e,\ell),
436: \]
437: where $g$ is the gate name, $I$ is the input surface submitted to that gate,
438: $d$ is the recorded decision, $e$ is the evidence pointer supporting the
439: decision, and $\ell$ is the evidence level.  A pass record is assigned to a
440: claim certificate only when its evidence pointer is contained in the claim's
441: evidence surface, in a submitted manifest or table row, in a bundled snapshot, or
442: in an explicit historical-evidence boundary.
443: 
444: A \emph{publication certificate} for a load-bearing claim $c$ is the finite
445: record
446: \[
447: \mathcal C(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B).
448: \]
449: Here $K$ is the nonempty finite set of claim kinds carried by $c$, $\ell$ is the
450: evidence level, $E$ is the evidence surface, $H$ is either a human-promotion
451: record or the marker that $c$ does not cross the intake-to-publication boundary,
452: $R$ gives one pass record, with the five fields above, for each gate in
453: $\bigcup_{k\in K}\Gamma(k)$, $D$ is present exactly when $K$ contains discovery
454: and then names the pinned discovery-gate source-interface rows used for the
455: claim, and $B$ records either the command-run fields or the explicit boundary
456: that no command-run assertion is made.  A certificate is \emph{locally
457: checkable} when these finite fields are present and every path, manifest row, or
458: log named by a field lies in the submitted artifact, the supplemental review
459: bundle, or the explicit path-verified historical boundary.
460: 
461: For later use we make the local check explicit as a finite verifier.  Given a
462: candidate record $\mathcal C(c)$, define $V(c,\mathcal C)$ to perform the
463: following schema checks, in order: (i) $K$ is a nonempty subset of the seven-kind
464: domain and $\ell$ is either path-verified or command-run; (ii) every element of
465: the finite evidence surface $E$ is a cited submitted path, review-bundle path,
466: manifest row, log path, pinned commit, or explicit historical-evidence boundary;
467: (iii) for every gate in $\bigcup_{k\in K}\Gamma(k)$, the field $R$ contains a pass
468: record with gate name, input surface, decision, evidence pointer, and evidence
469: level, and the evidence pointer is tied to $E$ or to a named manifest, table,
470: bundled snapshot, or historical boundary; (iv) $H$ is a concrete human-promotion record when
471: the claim crosses the intake-to-publication boundary and otherwise records that
472: no such boundary is crossed; (v) $D$ is present exactly when discovery lies in
473: $K$, and then names the pinned discovery-gate source-interface rows used by the
474: claim; and (vi) $B$ either records command, source commit, environment, exit code,
475: and log path for command-run evidence or explicitly records that no command-run
476: assertion is made.
477: \end{definition}
478: 
479: \begin{proposition}[Finite certificate schema verifier]
480: \label{prop:finite-certificate-schema-verifier}
481: For every load-bearing manuscript claim $c$ whose component kinds lie in the
482: seven-kind domain, $V(c,\mathcal C)$ is a finite, prose-insensitive
483: record-schema verifier for the declared publication certificate.  If $V$ accepts,
484: then $\mathcal C(c)$ is locally checkable at exactly its declared evidence level.
485: This is certificate-record verification only: it checks finite record shape,
486: dispatch, evidence pointers, and command-boundary discipline, not end-to-end
487: external semantic validation of the referenced artifacts or source theory.  If
488: $V$ rejects, then a reviewer can extract a finite bad subrecord consisting of the
489: first failed schema check and the fields on which that check depends.
490: \end{proposition}
491: 
492: \begin{proof}
493: The verifier inspects only the displayed tuple $\mathcal C(c)$, the finite
494: seven-kind domain, the finite dispatch table $\Gamma$, and the finite list of
495: paths, rows, commits, or logs cited by the record.  Since $K$ is required to be a
496: subset of the seven-kind domain, the set
497: \(\bigcup_{k\in K}\Gamma(k)\) is finite.  The checks over $E$, $R$, and the
498: command-run fields are therefore finite lookups in named manuscript or bundle
499: surfaces, not semantic judgments about generated prose.
500: 
501: If all six checks pass, the tuple has exactly the fields required in the
502: definition of a publication certificate: a finite kind set $K$, declared evidence
503: level $\ell$, evidence surface $E$, route-boundary field $H$, gate-record field
504: $R$, optional discovery field $D$ with the required presence condition, and
505: evidence-strength boundary $B$.  Check~(ii) is precisely the local-checkability
506: condition on cited paths, manifest rows, logs, pinned commits, and historical
507: boundaries.  Checks~(iii)--(vi) prevent the only possible escalations of the
508: declared level: missing gate passage, unrecorded route promotion, unsupported
509: discovery routing, and command-run assertion without command-run fields.  Thus an
510: accepted record is locally checkable at the level $\ell$ it declares, and no
511: stronger level is silently inferred.
512: 
513: If a check fails, the verifier stops at a finite test.  The bad subrecord is the
514: finite collection of fields read by that failed test: for example, $K$ and
515: $\Gamma$ for a gate-domain failure, $E$ for an evidence-surface failure, $K$,
516: $\Gamma$, $R$, and the cited evidence item for a gate-record failure, $H$ for a
517: promotion failure, $K$ and $D$ for a discovery-field failure, or $\ell$ and $B$
518: for an evidence-level failure.  This subrecord is independent of any surrounding
519: paragraph that may have described the claim.\qed
520: \end{proof}
521: 
522: \begin{theorem}[Record-acceptance exactness]
523: \label{thm:record-acceptance-exactness}
524: Fix the seven-kind dispatch table $\Gamma$, the two evidence levels, and the
525: certificate tuple format of Definition~\ref{def:operational-acceptance-interface}.
526: For a load-bearing claim $c$ and a finite candidate certificate
527: $\mathcal C(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B)$, define
528: $\mathsf{Acc}_{\Gamma}(c,\mathcal C)$ to mean that the following six finite
529: record clauses hold:
530: \begin{enumerate}
531: \item $K$ is a nonempty set of declared claim kinds in the seven-kind domain and
532: $\ell$ is one of the two evidence levels;
533: \item every item of $E$ is a submitted path, review-bundle path, manifest row,
534: log path, pinned commit, or explicit historical-evidence boundary available to
535: the reviewer at level $\ell$;
536: \item for every gate in $\bigcup_{k\in K}\Gamma(k)$, $R$ contains a pass record
537: with gate name, input surface, decision, evidence pointer, and evidence level,
538: and the pointer lies in $E$ or in a named submitted table, manifest row, bundled
539: snapshot, or historical boundary;
540: \item $H$ records human promotion exactly when the claim crosses the
541: intake-to-publication boundary, and otherwise records that no such boundary is
542: crossed;
543: \item $D$ is present exactly for discovery-kind claims and then names the pinned
544: discovery-gate source-interface rows used by the claim; and
545: \item $B$ records the command, source commit, environment, exit code, and log path
546: for command-run evidence, or records that no command-run assertion is made.
547: \end{enumerate}
548: Then the finite verifier $V$ accepts $\mathcal C(c)$ if and only if
549: $\mathsf{Acc}_{\Gamma}(c,\mathcal C)$ holds.  Moreover, if $V$ accepts a record
550: for $c$, the same record cannot certify any stronger reading $c^{+}$ that adds a
551: new claim kind, a stronger evidence level, an omitted route crossing, an omitted
552: discovery interface, an omitted pass record, or a command-run assertion: such a
553: reading has a finite bad subrecord of the corresponding clause.  Thus $V$ is
554: exact for this paper's finite record-acceptance relation, while remaining silent
555: about external semantic validity of the referenced theory or artifacts and about
556: the soundness of any deployed gate implementation beyond the recorded pass rows.
557: \end{theorem}
558: 
559: \begin{proof}
560: The definition of $V$ and the six clauses above use the same finite inputs.  The
561: first check of $V$ is clause~1.  The second check is clause~2.  The third check is
562: clause~3, including both assigned-gate coverage and the requirement that each
563: evidence pointer be tied to the declared review surface.  The fourth, fifth, and
564: sixth checks are exactly clauses~4, 5, and 6.  Therefore, if
565: $\mathsf{Acc}_{\Gamma}(c,\mathcal C)$ holds, every verifier check succeeds and
566: $V$ accepts.
567: 
568: Conversely, suppose $V$ accepts.  Reading the successful checks in order gives
569: precisely clauses~1--6: the kind set and evidence level are in the permitted
570: domains; the evidence surface is reviewer-available at the declared level; every
571: gate assigned by $\Gamma$ has a pass record with the required five fields and an
572: allowed pointer; promotion and non-promotion are separated by $H$; discovery-kind
573: claims and only discovery-kind claims carry $D$; and $B$ fixes the command-run
574: boundary.  Hence $\mathsf{Acc}_{\Gamma}(c,\mathcal C)$ holds.
575: 
576: For the final assertion, keep the accepted tuple fixed and consider a proposed
577: stronger reading $c^{+}$.  If $c^{+}$ adds a claim kind, the finite set of gates
578: assigned by $\Gamma$ grows unless the added kind is vacuous in this interface;
579: without the corresponding pass records clause~3 fails, and if the kind lies
580: outside the seven-kind domain clause~1 fails.  If $c^{+}$ raises the evidence
581: level to command-run, clause~6 fails unless the command, commit, environment,
582: exit code, and log path are present.  If it adds a route crossing, clause~4 fails
583: unless $H$ contains the human-promotion record.  If it adds discovery content,
584: clause~5 fails unless the pinned discovery rows are named.  If it asserts a new
585: gate-dependent conclusion without a pass record, clause~3 fails.  In each case
586: the failed clause reads only finitely many fields, so deleting irrelevant unread
587: fields gives an inclusion-minimal bad subrecord.  If none of the clauses changes,
588: then $c^{+}$ is not stronger in the record semantics: the certificate still
589: licenses only the same kind set, same evidence level, same gate records, same
590: route boundary, same discovery interface, and same command boundary.\qed
591: \end{proof}
592: 
593: \begin{theorem}[Finite-coordinate determination boundary]
594: \label{thm:finite-coordinate-determination-boundary}
595: Fix the dispatch table $\Gamma$ and the verifier $V$.  Let $F$ be the finite set of
596: coordinates read by $V$ from a certificate record, namely the claim-kind set,
597: declared evidence level, evidence surface, promotion field, gate-pass rows,
598: discovery-source rows, and command-boundary tuple.  If two ambient pipeline or
599: artifact states induce the same values of all coordinates in $F$ for a claim
600: $c$, then they induce the same record-acceptance decision and the same finite
601: publication certificate for $c$.  Consequently no property depending on a
602: coordinate outside $F$---for example a fresh Lean build result, a daemon trace,
603: an artifact semantic fact, or an external venue decision---is a consequence of
604: the accepted certificate unless that property is first encoded as an additional
605: finite certificate coordinate and the enlarged record is accepted.
606: \end{theorem}
607: 
608: \begin{proof}
609: The verifier $V$ is defined as an ordered list of six checks, and each check reads
610: only one of the coordinates listed in $F$ together with the fixed finite dispatch
611: table $\Gamma$.  If two ambient states induce the same values on $F$, then the
612: input tuple \((K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B)\) presented to $V$ is identical in the two
613: states.  Each of the six checks therefore has the same truth value in the two
614: states, so $V$ either accepts both records or rejects both records at the same
615: first failed finite field.  By Theorem~\ref{thm:record-acceptance-exactness}, an
616: accepted decision is equivalent to the same six-clause record-acceptance
617: semantics, hence the finite certificate determined by those clauses is also the
618: same.
619: 
620: Now let $Q$ be a property whose truth can vary while all coordinates in $F$ are
