900: kinds or stronger evidence levels that require their own records.  The human-promotion field $H$ separates
901: the route boundary from all other gates: it is either a concrete promotion
902: record or a finite marker that no such boundary is crossed.  Finally, when
903: discovery lies in $K$, the discovery field $D$ names the pinned source-interface
904: rows certified by Lemma~\ref{lem:source-interface-extraction-correctness} and
905: Propositions~\ref{prop:reviewable-source-snapshot-interface} and
906: \ref{prop:source-interface-record-file-consistency}; these rows are finite and
907: therefore locally checkable in the same way as the other certificate fields.
908: Thus the certificate is sufficient for a reviewer to check safety by examining a
909: finite list of fields and cited artifacts, not by trusting generated prose.
910: 
911: It remains to prove that the displayed obstruction list is complete.  Suppose an
912: accepted claim fails the publication-safety interface.  Choose an inclusion-minimal
913: subrecord of its acceptance entry that still witnesses failure.  If the failure
914: is that the claim is not tied to evidence at the declared evidence level, then
915: the minimal subrecord is type~1.  If evidence exists but some required gate is
916: unrecorded, the omitted gate belongs to $G(c)$ by the deterministic dispatch
917: proposition, giving type~2.  If all required non-route evidence is present but
918: the claim entered active publication state from intake or source material without
919: human promotion, the missing field is $H$, giving type~3.  If the claim is a
920: discovery claim and the problem is that statement-only, code-only, mechanical,
921: compression-only, or classifier-scored output was accepted without the pinned
922: certificate, ledger, lineage, and boundary interface, the missing discovery
923: field is $D$, giving type~4.  The only remaining way to fail while the preceding
924: fields are present is to assert command-run strength without the command-run
925: fields required by the evidence-level definition; that is type~5.  These cases
926: cover the definitions of acceptance entry, gate-soundness, human promotion,
927: discovery routing, and evidence level.  Minimality removes irrelevant fields and
928: leaves exactly one of the five obstruction skeletons.  Conversely, if no bad
929: subrecord of type~1--5 is present, then each schema check in
930: Proposition~\ref{prop:finite-certificate-schema-verifier} succeeds: the evidence
931: surface is present at the declared level, every required gate has its recorded
932: pass, the route-boundary field is correct, discovery rows are present exactly
933: when required, and command-run strength is not asserted without command-run
934: fields.  Hence the verifier accepts the certificate and the publication-safety
935: interface holds for $c$ at the declared evidence level.
936: 
937: The final sentence follows from the construction.  The verifier reads only the
938: finite certificate fields and the finite dispatch table, so the theorem
939: classifies certificate failures for review.  It does not assert a lower bound,
940: complexity separation, automated theorem-proving method, or fresh run of any
941: external command.\qed
942: \end{proof}
943: 
944: \begin{proposition}[Gate-interface separation]
945: \label{prop:gate-interface-separation}
946: The promotion, overlap, submission-state, and theorem-content delta gates are
947: separate deterministic interfaces.  None can be replaced by passage of another
948: one when a load-bearing claim has the corresponding component.
949: \end{proposition}
950: 
951: \begin{proof}
952: Each named gate has a distinct invariant and evidence surface in the operational
953: definition.  Promotion asks whether a candidate has crossed the human
954: publication boundary; its evidence is the active-paper directory and pipeline
955: metadata.  Overlap asks whether the route duplicates or conflicts with a sibling
956: route; its evidence is route identity, overlap ledgers, submitted-sibling paths,
957: and board state.  Submission-state asks whether the proposed publication action
958: is compatible with submission markers, venue state, and submission-pack metadata.
959: The theorem-content delta gate asks whether an asserted extension contains
960: load-bearing theorem growth; its evidence is an inventory, hard-lint surface, or
961: delta record.  These predicates are logically independent at the interface
962: level: an active paper can still overlap a submitted sibling, a route with no
963: overlap can still have an impermissible submission state, and a compiling edit in
964: a permissible route can still lack theorem-content delta.  Therefore a
965: load-bearing claim with any one of these components must pass that component's
966: own gate, and passage through the others cannot supply the missing evidence.\qed
967: \end{proof}
968: 
969: \begin{proposition}[Scheduler selection is advisory before discovery gating]
970: \label{prop:scheduler-selection-advisory}
971: Let $s$ be a scheduler or critical-path score attached to a candidate claim
972: $c$.  If $s$ recommends selecting $c$, then the recommendation is a
973: work-selection claim and by itself can only pass the scheduler gate.  If $c$ is
974: also asserted to be a discovery or classifier-shifting contribution in a
975: gate-sound pipeline, then the accepted mixed claim must pass both the scheduler
976: gate and the discovery gate.
977: Consequently, critical-path scores may prioritize review order, and the imported
978: classifier-shift selection rule may break ties among otherwise equal discovery
979: potential coordinates, but neither score nor recommendation accepts a
980: classifier-shift discovery unless the discovery gate also supplies the required
981: certificate, ledger, and lineage witnesses.
982: \end{proposition}
983: 
984: \begin{proof}
985: By the definition of $\Gamma$, a scheduler recommendation has claim kind
986: work-selection, so its atomic gate is the scheduler gate.  The scheduler gate's
987: evidence surface records a score, backlog window, or analogous critical-path
988: priority; none of these fields is a semantic naming certificate, a ledger
989: witness, a DNA-complete theorem genome, a score certificate for a discovery
990: claim, a lineage witness, or a not-claimed boundary.  Hence scheduler passage
991: alone records only that $c$ is an eligible or prioritized work item.
992: 
993: Now suppose that the same recorded assertion also says that $c$ is a discovery
994: or classifier-shifting contribution.  Then the assertion is mixed: it has a
995: work-selection component and a discovery component.  Proposition~\ref{prop:claim-kind-dispatch}
996: therefore requires passage through every gate in the union assigned by $\Gamma$,
997: namely the scheduler gate for the work-selection component and the pinned
998: discovery gate for the discovery component.  The source-interface record in
999: Table~\ref{tab:source-interface-record} includes the imported classifier-change
1000: selection theorem only in its bounded form: with positive classifier-change
1001: weight and all other coordinates fixed, such a selection operator favors the
1002: classifier-changing candidate.  The same source-interface record also includes
1003: pipeline safety, which requires certificate, ledger, genome, score, lineage, and
1004: boundary witnesses for accepted discovery.  Combining these two imported
1005: interfaces gives the stated conclusion: scheduling and classifier-shift scoring
1006: can advise selection order, but discovery acceptance still occurs only through
1007: the discovery gate.\qed
1008: \end{proof}
1009: 
1010: \begin{theorem}[Constructive finite publication-safety interface]
1011: \label{thm:publication-safety-interface}
1012: Consider a theory-to-paper pipeline with the operational interface above.  Assume
1013: that every load-bearing claim in an active manuscript is either rejected or has an
1014: acceptance entry with an evidence surface; that the pipeline is gate-sound for
1015: acceptance, meaning that a recorded acceptance entry is present only after every
1016: gate assigned by $\Gamma$ to the claim kind has already produced a pass record;
1017: that every advisory output is demoted unless the deterministic gate set
1018: $\Gamma$ for its claim kind passes; that discovery claims are checked through
1019: the pinned discovery-gate interface certified by
1020: Lemma~\ref{lem:source-interface-extraction-correctness} and
1021: Propositions~\ref{prop:reviewable-source-snapshot-interface},
1022: \ref{prop:source-interface-record-file-consistency}, and
1023: \ref{prop:source-interface-evidence-level-separation}, in particular the
1024: separated manual/path-verified and executable finite-record levels for the
1025: pipeline safety and main pipeline theorem labels; and
1026: that no inactive intake seed is treated as publication work without human
1027: promotion.  Then the nontrivial output of the interface is a finite certificate
1028: constructor.  For every accepted load-bearing claim $c$ it constructs, from the
1029: acceptance entry and submitted evidence surfaces, a record
1030: \[
1031: \mathsf{Cert}_{\Gamma}(c)=\mathcal C(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B)
1032: \]
1033: accepted by the finite schema verifier of
1034: Proposition~\ref{prop:finite-certificate-schema-verifier}; equivalently, by
1035: the finite-record exactness of Theorem~\ref{thm:record-acceptance-exactness}, the constructed record satisfies
1036: the record-acceptance semantics for the dispatch table $\Gamma$.  This is the
1037: maximal conclusion determined by the submitted finite coordinates: if a stronger
1038: reading $c^+$ of $c$ asserts external end-to-end compiler correctness, current
1039: execution of unrecorded gates, proof-assistant correctness, current formal-source
1040: currency, dynamic artifact semantics, or venue acceptance, then $c^+$ is accepted
1041: only after the certificate is enlarged by the additional claim kind, evidence
1042: surface, gate pass records, promotion field, or command-run tuple required for
1043: that stronger reading.
1044: Consequently the claim has a recorded evidence surface, a declared evidence
1045: boundary, and a prior pass record for every gate required for its claim kind.
1046: Moreover, accepted discovery claims inherit the bounded pinned source-interface
1047: consequences that statement-only, code-only, mechanical-expansion, and
1048: compression-only outputs are not accepted as discovery without the required
1049: certificate, ledger, and lineage witnesses.  Any purported accepted claim without
1050: such finite certificate data is rejected by one of the five obstruction skeletons
1051: in Theorem~\ref{thm:finite-certificate-obstruction-skeleton}.  For the current
1052: package, the hypotheses are witnessed by the machine-readable evidence map in
1053: Proposition~\ref{prop:machine-readable-certificate-records}, the acceptance
1054: ledger in Proposition~\ref{prop:current-package-acceptance-certificate-ledger},
1055: and the four path-complete case witnesses of
1056: Proposition~\ref{prop:path-complete-case-witnesses}, with the current-package
1057: bounded instantiation isolated in
1058: Corollary~\ref{cor:current-package-path-verified-instantiation} and the
1059: case-snapshot non-rerun boundary isolated in
1060: Corollary~\ref{cor:case-snapshot-non-rerun-rigidity}.  The finite-coordinate
1061: boundary of Theorem~\ref{thm:finite-coordinate-determination-boundary} is part of
1062: the conclusion: the constructed certificate determines exactly the finite record
1063: coordinates it reads and cannot determine any unrecorded build, daemon, artifact,
1064: or venue coordinate.  Thus the package instance is a certificate-construction and
1065: certificate-checking theorem for the finite records actually supplied.  It is not
1066: an unconditional correctness theorem for an arbitrary implementation: it does not
1067: independently prove that such an implementation is gate-sound, that every
1068: possible gate in the surrounding project was run for this package, that
1069: Lean-facing contextual rows are current formal-source certificates, or that
1070: path-verified rows are command-run evidence.
1071: \end{theorem}
1072: 
1073: \begin{proof}
1074: Let $c$ be an accepted load-bearing claim in the manuscript.  The conclusion has
1075: three parts.  The first part is the constructor.  The acceptance-entry hypothesis
1076: supplies the claim-kind set $K$, evidence level $\ell$, and evidence surface $E$,
1077: so the decision is attached to a source path, artifact path, command log,
1078: inventory, or witness record rather than to generated prose alone.  Gate-soundness
1079: supplies the pass-record field $R$ for every gate assigned by $\Gamma$.  If
1080: accepting $c$ crosses from intake or source material into daemon-visible
1081: publication work, the promotion assumption supplies the human-promotion field
1082: $H$; otherwise $H$ records that no such boundary is crossed.  The evidence-level
1083: definition supplies the boundary field $B$: either the command-run fields are
1084: present or the record explicitly remains path-verified.  If $c$ is a discovery
1085: claim, the discovery-routing assumption supplies $D$ from the pinned
1086: source-interface rows; otherwise $D$ is absent as required by the certificate
1087: schema.  Thus the constructor
1088: \(\mathsf{Cert}_{\Gamma}(c)=\mathcal C(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B)\) is determined by
1089: finite submitted records and is locally checkable whenever its cited paths and
1090: manifest rows lie in the submitted artifact, review bundle, or explicit
1091: historical boundary.  The same construction verifies
1092: $\mathsf{Acc}_{\Gamma}(c,\mathcal C)$, so
1093: The finite-record exactness of Theorem~\ref{thm:record-acceptance-exactness} identifies the constructed
1094: certificate with the paper's independently stated record-acceptance semantics,
1095: not merely with an informal unpacking of the tuple.
1096: 
1097: The maximality assertion is also finite.  By
1098: Theorem~\ref{thm:finite-coordinate-determination-boundary}, the schema verifier is
1099: a function only of the tuple \((K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B)\), the dispatch table, and the
1100: cited submitted records.  Hence two surrounding implementations, formal-source
1101: trees, artifact runs, or venue states that agree on these submitted coordinates
1102: receive the same certificate decision.  A stronger reading $c^+$ therefore has
1103: only two possible forms.  If it keeps the same tuple, then the verifier has no
1104: coordinate from which to distinguish the stronger hidden assertion, so the
1105: accepted conclusion is still only the finite certificate conclusion just
1106: constructed.  If it enlarges the claim kind, evidence level, submitted boundary,
1107: discovery requirement, or fresh-run assertion, then the dispatch table or
1108: evidence-level definition asks for additional finite fields: further pass records
1109: in $R$, further evidence in $E$, a different boundary $B$, a human-promotion
1110: record $H$, discovery rows $D$, or the command-run tuple.  When those fields are
1111: absent, Theorem~\ref{thm:finite-certificate-obstruction-skeleton} extracts a
1112: minimal bad subrecord.  Thus the theorem gives a certificate-construction theorem
1113: and a finite-record maximality theorem, not an unlogged end-to-end correctness
1114: theorem.
1115: 
1116: Propositions~\ref{prop:claim-kind-dispatch} and
1117: \ref{prop:gate-interface-separation} identify the required finite gate set:
1118: formal-source claims use build and axiom gates, traceability claims use inventory
1119: and marker gates, route claims use promotion, overlap, and submission-state
1120: gates, artifact claims use status and limitation-ledger gates, submission claims
1121: use submission-pack gates, extension-style discovery claims use the
1122: theorem-content delta gate together with the pinned discovery gate,
1123: work-selection claims use the scheduler gate, and mixed claims use the union.
1124: Thus $c$ has a prior pass record for the gates required by its kind.  The
1125: advisory-output assumption prevents an agent draft, review packet, score, or
1126: repair proposal from being promoted by prose alone: without the relevant pass
1127: records it remains demoted.  The promotion assumption similarly prevents an
1128: inactive intake seed from becoming publication work merely because a local source
1129: path exists.
1130: 
1131: If $c$ is a discovery claim, the discovery-routing assumption sends it through
1132: the pinned discovery-gate interface.  Proposition~\ref{prop:reviewable-source-snapshot-interface}
1133: supplies the corresponding reviewer-facing snapshot interface, so this routing
1134: does not depend on a reviewer's access to the author's absolute source path.  The
1135: record-file consistency certificate in
1136: Proposition~\ref{prop:source-interface-record-file-consistency} further shows, at
1137: the finite record-comparison level, that the manuscript table, JSON mirror,
1138: review-bundle manifest, digest, line count, and bundled source snapshot name the
1139: same finite imported interface.  The
1140: source-interface table records the imported statements used here:
1141: statement-only, code-only, mechanical-expansion, and compression-only records do
1142: not become accepted discovery claims without the required certificate, ledger,
1143: and lineage witnesses, and classifier-shift selection remains bounded by the
1144: discovery gate as shown in Proposition~\ref{prop:scheduler-selection-advisory}.
1145: Finally apply Theorem~\ref{thm:finite-certificate-obstruction-skeleton}.  If an
1146: allegedly accepted claim lacks the certificate just constructed, its failure has
1147: a minimal bad subrecord of type 1--5: missing evidence surface, missing gate
1148: record, missing promotion field, missing discovery-interface rows, or unsupported
1149: command-run escalation.  Each type contradicts one of the workflow assumptions
1150: above or demotes the claim to a weaker evidence level.  The stated safety
1151: interface follows.\qed
1152: \end{proof}
1153: 
1154: \begin{corollary}[Finite-record boundary for gate soundness]
1155: \label{cor:finite-record-gate-soundness-boundary}
1156: Under the hypotheses of Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}, the
1157: publication-safety conclusion is invariant under replacement of the surrounding
1158: implementation by any other implementation with the same submitted acceptance
1159: entries, evidence surfaces, promotion fields, discovery-interface rows, and
1160: evidence-level boundaries.  Therefore the theorem cannot be used, without an
1161: additional submitted gate-soundness certificate, to infer external workflow
1162: correctness, current execution of unrecorded gates, Lean correctness, artifact
1163: semantic validity, or venue acceptance.  Conversely, any manuscript assertion
1164: that tries to promote the finite certificate constructor to one of those stronger
1165: implementation claims has a finite overclaim witness: either the required field
1166: is absent from \(\mathcal C(c)\), or the row's declared evidence level exceeds
1167: the cited certificate surface.
1168: \end{corollary}
1169: 
1170: \begin{proof}
1171: The constructor in Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface} reads only the
1172: finite tuple \(\mathcal C(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B)\).  Here \(K\) is the claim-kind
1173: set assigned by the dispatch table, \(\ell\) is the declared evidence level,
1174: \(E\) is the submitted evidence surface, \(H\) is the human-promotion field,
1175: \(R\) is the finite list of recorded pass rows, \(D\) is the pinned
1176: discovery-interface field when the claim has a discovery component, and \(B\) is
1177: the evidence boundary.  If another implementation supplies the same values for
1178: these fields, the same finite schema verifier receives the same input record and
1179: therefore gives the same certificate-construction conclusion by
1180: Proposition~\ref{prop:finite-certificate-schema-verifier} and
