620: Now let $Q$ be a property whose truth can vary while all coordinates in $F$ are
621: held fixed.  Then there exist two ambient states with the same certificate tuple
622: and the same verifier decision but different truth values for $Q$.  A conclusion
623: whose truth changes under such an $F$-preserving substitution is not determined by
624: the accepted certificate.  To make $Q$ load-bearing, the operational interface
625: must add a finite coordinate recording the required evidence: for a build or
626: daemon trace this is a command-run tuple; for an artifact semantic fact this is
627: an artifact pass record or rerun log; and for a venue decision this is an
628: external evidence surface and the corresponding route/submission record.  Without
629: that enlargement, Theorem~\ref{thm:record-acceptance-exactness} supplies only the
630: original finite-record conclusion.\qed
631: \end{proof}
632: 
633: \begin{proposition}[Machine-readable certificate records]
634: \label{prop:machine-readable-certificate-records}
635: For the current presentation package, the finite verifier
636: $V$ of Proposition~\ref{prop:finite-certificate-schema-verifier}, with the
637: record-acceptance semantics of
638: Theorem~\ref{thm:record-acceptance-exactness}, has an executable record-level
639: instance over the review bundle.  The schema file
640: \path{review_bundle/certificate_schema.json}, the pass-record ledger
641: \path{review_bundle/current_package_pass_records.json}, the primary-interface map
642: \path{review_bundle/submission_interface_map.json}, the primary-claim inventory
643: \path{review_bundle/primary_claim_inventory.json}, the verifier script
644: \path{review_bundle/verify_certificate_records.py}, and the recorded run
645: \path{review_bundle/certificate_verification_run.log} instantiate the verifier at
646: the path-verified level for entries $a_1,\ldots,a_6$.  Each pass record in the
647: ledger has the five fields \emph{gate name}, \emph{input surface},
648: \emph{decision}, \emph{evidence pointer}, and \emph{evidence level}.  The
649: machine-readable submission-interface map is locked to rows \path{sim1}--\path{sim4}
650: of Table~\ref{tab:submission-interface-map} by its row identifiers, certificates,
651: surfaces, and evidence levels; the primary-claim inventory is locked to rows
652: \path{pc1}--\path{pc12} by its row identifiers, source locations, row classes,
653: and evidence levels.  These executable locks check the finite record interface;
654: full semantic equality between prose paraphrases and mathematical meaning, and
655: path completeness beyond the declared surfaces, remain the manual audit boundary
656: stated in the row classes.
657: \end{proposition}
658: 
659: \begin{proof}
660: All objects in the statement are finite files in the submitted review bundle, so
661: the claim is a finite record check.  The manifest
662: \path{review_bundle/REVIEW_BUNDLE_MANIFEST.json} contains top-level fields named
663: \path{certificate_schema}, \path{current_package_pass_records},
664: \path{submission_interface_map}, \path{primary_claim_inventory},
665: \path{verifier_script}, and \path{verifier_run_log}; these fields point to the six
666: bundle files named in the statement.  Thus the executable verifier is not an
667: implicit prose convention but a submitted artifact surface.
668: 
669: The schema file lists the seven claim kinds, the two evidence levels, the same
670: gate dispatch $\Gamma$ used in the supplement, and the required pass-record
671: fields $(g,I,d,e,\ell)$.  The pass-record ledger has exactly six entries,
672: $a_1,\ldots,a_6$.  For each entry it records a nonempty claim-kind set, the
673: path-verified evidence level, a finite evidence surface, the route-boundary or
674: human-promotion field, pass records, the discovery-interface field, and the
675: evidence boundary.  Inspecting the six entries gives the required gate coverage:
676: $a_1$ has inventory and marker-existence records; $a_2$ has promotion, overlap,
677: submission-state, and submission-pack records; $a_3$ has promotion, overlap, and
678: submission-state records; $a_4$ has promotion, overlap, submission-state, and
679: submission-pack records; $a_5$ has pinned-discovery and theorem-content-delta
680: records; and $a_6$ has status and limitation-ledger records.  These are exactly
681: the unions of the gate sets assigned by $\Gamma$ to the claim-kind sets displayed
682: in Table~\ref{tab:current-acceptance-ledger}.  The only row with discovery kind
683: is $a_5$, and it is the only row with a non-null discovery-interface field; every
684: row is path-verified and therefore carries a boundary saying that no command-run
685: assertion is made.
686: 
687: The script \path{review_bundle/verify_certificate_records.py} implements precisely
688: these finite checks: required manifest fields, entries $a_1$--$a_6$, kind-domain
689: membership, evidence-level membership, assigned-gate coverage, the five
690: pass-record fields, evidence-level agreement, discovery-field discipline, the
691: path-verified boundary condition, exact row locks for \path{sim1}--\path{sim4}
692: against the submission-interface JSON fields, and row-class locks for
693: \path{pc1}--\path{pc12} against the primary-claim inventory locations, statuses,
694: and evidence levels.  The recorded log
695: \path{review_bundle/certificate_verification_run.log} records a successful run of
696: that script over the submitted files and states the boundary that no Lean build,
697: publication-daemon run, or Rule110 dynamic artifact rerun is being certified.
698: Consequently the executable artifact proves exactly the schema-level instance of
699: $V$ claimed here.  By the finite-record exactness of Theorem~\ref{thm:record-acceptance-exactness}, this is also
700: an instance of the paper's finite record-acceptance semantics: the executable
701: record accepts exactly the six current-package certificates and no stronger
702: evidence level or omitted gate semantics.
703: 
704: Finally, \path{review_bundle/submission_interface_map.json} has rows
705: \path{sim1}--\path{sim4}.  The verifier now rejects a mutation of any row's
706: primary claim text, certificate list, row-or-manifest surface list, or evidence
707: level, so the JSON file is an executable finite mirror of the interface table at
708: that declared field level.  The file
709: \path{review_bundle/primary_claim_inventory.json} lists the concrete primary-note
710: assertions as rows \path{pc1}--\path{pc12}; every load-bearing row names a
711: certificate, row, manifest surface, or bounded-context status and declares an
712: evidence level, and the verifier locks each row's identifier, source location,
713: status class, and evidence level.  Thus the primary note has a complete finite
714: claim inventory at the declared review fields, and no additional primary
715: load-bearing assertion is licensed by the machine-readable interface.  The proof
716: does not assert that the script decides semantic paraphrase equality or discovers
717: undeclared paths; those remain the manual audit obligations represented by the
718: table rows and by Proposition~\ref{prop:primary-inventory-freshness-criterion}.\qed
719: \end{proof}
720: 
721: \begin{theorem}[Executable record non-escalation]
722: \label{thm:executable-record-non-escalation}
723: Let $F$ be the finite field projection read by
724: \path{review_bundle/verify_certificate_records.py}: manifest-field presence,
725: entries $a_1$--$a_6$, claim-kind membership, evidence-level membership,
726: assigned-gate coverage, pass-record fields, evidence-level agreement,
727: discovery-field discipline, path-verified boundary status, row locks for
728: \path{sim1}--\path{sim4}, and row-class locks for \path{pc1}--\path{pc12}.  Among
729: all assertions about the current review bundle that are functions only of this
730: projection, Proposition~\ref{prop:machine-readable-certificate-records} proves the
731: maximal executable claim: the six current-package certificates satisfy the finite
732: record-acceptance relation of Theorem~\ref{thm:record-acceptance-exactness} at the
733: declared path-verified fields, and no accepted row carries a command-run
734: boundary.  In particular, the executable verifier cannot certify any strictly
735: stronger assertion whose truth depends on prose-to-semantics equality,
736: independent extraction of claims from the manuscript, completeness of paths not
737: declared in the records, or the external semantics of a Lean development,
738: publication daemon, artifact suite, or evaluator.
739: \end{theorem}
740: 
741: \begin{proof}
742: By the proof of Proposition~\ref{prop:machine-readable-certificate-records}, the
743: script reads exactly the finite projection $F$ listed in the statement and rejects
744: mutations of the locked fields.  Hence every executable assertion made by that
745: script is constant on the equivalence classes of review bundles with the same
746: projection $F$.  On this quotient, the six ledger entries, their kind sets, their
747: evidence levels, their assigned gates, their pass-record fields, their discovery
748: boundaries, and their path-verified non-command boundaries are all fixed.  The
749: finite-record acceptance exactness theorem then identifies precisely what this fixed
750: data entails: acceptance of those six certificates in the finite relation
751: $\mathsf{Acc}_{\Gamma}$ and rejection of stronger readings that add kinds, raise
752: the evidence level, omit route or discovery fields, omit pass records, or assert
753: command-run evidence without the required command tuple.
754: 
755: Now consider any proposed stronger assertion of one of the four types named in
756: the statement.  Its truth is not determined by $F$.  Prose-to-semantics equality
757: depends on interpreting manuscript language against mathematical meanings, while
758: $F$ contains only row identifiers, selected text locks, classes, locations,
759: certificate lists, surfaces, and evidence levels.  Independent extraction depends
760: on an extraction procedure over the manuscript, while $F$ contains the submitted
761: inventory rather than the result of an independently specified extractor.
762: Completeness of undeclared paths depends on paths outside the finite surfaces
763: read by the verifier.  External artifact semantics depends on running or
764: semantically validating objects whose command, source state, environment, exit
765: code, and log path are not present in the path-verified rows.  Therefore two
766: packages can agree on $F$ while differing on such a stronger assertion.  Since a
767: function of $F$ has the same value on both packages, no executable claim proved by
768: this verifier can certify that stronger assertion.  The maximal executable
769: record-level claim is exactly the one stated in
770: Proposition~\ref{prop:machine-readable-certificate-records}.\qed
771: \end{proof}
772: 
773: \begin{theorem}[Executable certificate-construction invariant]
774: \label{thm:executable-certificate-construction-invariant}
775: For the submitted review bundle, let $G$ be the union of the finite fields read by
776: the two executable verifiers
777: \path{review_bundle/verify_source_interface_record.py} and
778: \path{review_bundle/verify_certificate_records.py}.  Thus $G$ contains the ten
779: source-interface table triples, the JSON source-interface records, the pinned
780: source snapshot path, digest, line count, declared source commit and line ranges,
781: the six current-package pass-record entries $a_1,\ldots,a_6$, the submission-map
782: rows \path{sim1}--\path{sim4}, the primary-inventory row locks
783: \path{pc1}--\path{pc12}, and the two recorded successful verifier logs.  On the
784: equivalence class of packages with the same projection $G$, the publication-safety
785: interface has a unique executable finite certificate construction: the imported
786: discovery-gate interface is the ten-row checked source interface of
787: Proposition~\ref{prop:source-interface-record-file-consistency}, the accepted
788: current-package certificates are exactly the six records of
789: Proposition~\ref{prop:machine-readable-certificate-records}, and any stronger
790: reading that changes the source interface, adds an accepted row, raises the
791: evidence level, adds a command-run assertion, or asserts external semantic or
792: venue correctness is not determined by $G$ and is rejected at the finite-record
793: boundary unless new certificate fields and verifier records are supplied.
794: \end{theorem}
795: 
796: \begin{proof}
797: The first executable verifier reads only the manuscript source-interface table,
798: \path{source_interface_record.json}, the \path{pinned_source_snapshot} object of
799: \path{review_bundle/REVIEW_BUNDLE_MANIFEST.json}, and the bundled source snapshot.
800: Proposition~\ref{prop:source-interface-record-file-consistency} proves that these
801: fields agree on the ordered ten triples, the original path, the source commit, the
802: ten line ranges, the snapshot digest, the snapshot line count, and the containment
803: of each imported label in its declared range.  Hence every package with the same
804: projection $G$ has the same executable imported discovery-gate interface, and no
805: table-only, JSON-only, manifest-only, stale-digest, stale-line-count, or
806: out-of-range imported row can be accepted inside that projection.
807: 
808: The second executable verifier reads the manifest fields, the certificate schema,
809: the six pass-record entries, the submission-interface map, and the primary-claim
810: inventory.  Proposition~\ref{prop:machine-readable-certificate-records} proves
811: that these fields instantiate the finite verifier $V$ for exactly rows
812: $a_1,\ldots,a_6$ at the path-verified level, with the displayed gate coverage,
813: discovery-field discipline, row locks, and non-command boundary.  Therefore every
814: package with the same projection $G$ has the same six accepted current-package
815: certificates and the same absence of command-run evidence in those certificates.
816: The finite-record exactness theorem,
817: Theorem~\ref{thm:record-acceptance-exactness}, identifies these accepted records
818: with the record-acceptance relation and rejects stronger readings that require
819: additional claim kinds, evidence surfaces, promotion fields, discovery fields,
820: pass rows, or command-run tuples.
821: 
822: Combining the two paragraphs gives the stated uniqueness on the $G$-projection:
823: the discovery component of any accepted current-package claim is forced through
824: the same checked ten-row source interface, and the publication component is forced
825: through the same six checked certificate rows.  Any proposed stronger assertion
826: listed in the statement either changes one of the finite fields of $G$, in which
827: case it is not a package in the same equivalence class, or leaves $G$ unchanged,
828: in which case the two verifiers receive identical inputs and can return only the
829: same finite-record conclusions.  Such an unchanged projection contains no
830: coordinate for external theorem truth, proof-assistant correctness, unlogged
831: daemon execution, artifact semantic validity, or venue acceptance.  Those claims
832: therefore require an enlarged certificate and additional executable records, and
833: without them they are outside the accepted finite-record interface.\qed
834: \end{proof}
835: 
836: \begin{proposition}[Deterministic claim-kind dispatch]
837: \label{prop:claim-kind-dispatch}
838: For every load-bearing manuscript claim whose kind lies in the seven-kind domain
839: above, $\Gamma$ assigns a unique finite set of deterministic gates.  In a
840: pipeline that is gate-sound for acceptance, a mixed load-bearing claim may be
841: used as accepted work only if its acceptance entry records passage through every
842: gate in the union assigned to its component kinds.
843: \end{proposition}
844: 
845: \begin{proof}
846: The seven atomic clauses in the definition of $\Gamma$ assign one explicitly named
847: finite gate set to each atomic claim kind.  Hence an atomic claim has a unique
848: assigned gate set.  For a mixed claim, the component-kind set is finite because
849: it is a subset of the seven-kind domain; taking the union of the corresponding
850: finite gate sets is deterministic and finite.  Gate-soundness for acceptance
851: requires the acceptance entry of a load-bearing claim to record passage through
852: every gate assigned by $\Gamma$.  If a component gate of a mixed claim were
853: omitted, then the projection of the claim to that component kind would lack its
854: assigned pass record.  Such an entry would not be gate-sound.  Therefore accepted
855: mixed claims in a gate-sound pipeline must pass every gate in the union.\qed
856: \end{proof}
857: 
858: \begin{theorem}[Finite certificate obstruction skeleton]
859: \label{thm:finite-certificate-obstruction-skeleton}
860: Let $c$ be a load-bearing manuscript claim whose component kinds lie in the
861: seven-kind domain.  The verifier of
862: Proposition~\ref{prop:finite-certificate-schema-verifier} gives the following
863: complete audit classification at the declared evidence level.  A certificate for
864: $c$ passes the publication-safety interface if and only if it has no bad
865: subrecord of the following five types:
866: \begin{enumerate}
867: \item missing evidence surface for the declared evidence level;
868: \item missing pass record for a gate in $\bigcup_{k\in K}\Gamma(k)$;
869: \item missing human-promotion record when the claim crosses from intake or
870: source material into active publication work;
871: \item discovery escalation without the pinned discovery-gate source-interface
872: rows for certificate, ledger, lineage, and boundary witnesses; or
873: \item command-run escalation without command, source commit, environment, exit
874: code, and log path.
875: \end{enumerate}
876: Equivalently, every unsafe accepted claim contains an inclusion-minimal finite
877: bad subrecord of one of these five types, and deleting all other fields preserves
878: the same rejection by the verifier.  This is an audit-skeleton theorem for the
879: software-workshop route: it classifies finite certificate failures and makes no
880: claim about theorem-proving complexity or about fresh execution of the
881: underlying workflow.
882: \end{theorem}
883: 
884: \begin{proof}
885: Let $K$ be the finite set of component kinds of $c$.  Since $K$ is a subset of
886: the seven-kind domain, Proposition~\ref{prop:claim-kind-dispatch} gives a unique
887: finite required gate set
888: \[
889: G(c)=\bigcup_{k\in K}\Gamma(k).
890: \]
891: The certificate field $R$ is indexed by exactly this finite set, so checking
892: gate passage is a finite lookup: each $g\in G(c)$ must have a pass record and the
893: record must cite an item of the finite evidence surface $E$.  The evidence-level
894: field $\ell$ and boundary field $B$ make the same lookup finite for evidence
895: strength: at path-verified level the certificate must name the source, artifact,
896: pinned commit, local publication path, or gate-decision surface used by the
897: claim; at command-run level it must additionally name command, source commit,
898: environment, exit code, and log path.  Neither lookup interprets artifact
899: semantics, reruns Lean, or predicts editorial outcomes; those are stronger claim
900: kinds or stronger evidence levels that require their own records.  The human-promotion field $H$ separates
