--- sections ---
60: section Problem and contribution
259: section Architecture
699: section Operational interface
728: subsection Abstract finite-record interface
3541: subsection Primary-claim inventory audit
3660: subsection Current-package instantiation
4246: section Gate summary
4248: subsection Case-study witness protocol
4377: section Case studies
4581: section Evidence boundary
4583: subsection Primary--supplement interface
5593: subsection Review-bundle and archive-equivalence condition
7380: subsection Command-run boundary
7952: section Conclusion and support-boundary summary
--- env summary ---
158|proposition|Final package-shape convention|prop:final-package-shape-convention|For the current presentation package there is a single source-level package shape. The primary article is \path{submission_abstract.tex}; the selected technical supplement is \path{main.tex}; the selected bounded theorem-obligation ledger consists of \path{theorem_inventory.json} and \path{theorem_inventory.md}; and the selected supplemental support surface is the finite tuple \path{theorem_inventory.json}, \path{theorem_inventory.md}, and exact inclusion of \path{review_bundle/} with the final 
208|theorem|Nested six-row and seven-row package states|thm:nested-package-states|Let $P^{+}_{6}$ denote the current row-frozen certificate state whose accepted rows are exactly $a_1,\ldots,a_6$ in Table~\ref{tab:current-acceptance-ledger}. Let $P^{+}_{7}$ denote the enlarged submitted support state obtained by adjoining the single theorem-ledger row $a_7$ whose submitted coordinate is \path{theorem_inventory.json}. Then $P^{+}_{6}\subset P^{+}_{7}$ as finite record surfaces, and the inclusion is conservative for the first six certificates: every acceptance decision, evidence
273|definition|Architecture-axis map|def:architecture-axis-map|The compiler architecture uses five disjoint evidence axes. An accepted claim may read evidence from an axis only at the admissible evidence level shown in the displayed axis map; the negative boundary in the last column is part of the claim certificate and cannot be discharged by prose from another axis. \small {\textwidth}{p{.16\textwidth}p{.27\textwidth}p{.27\textwidth}X} \toprule Axis & Role in this paper & Admissible evidence & Negative boundary \\ \midrule BEDC source theory & finite-kerne
312|proposition|Axis non-escalation|prop:architecture-axis-non-escalation|In any record-gate-sound package using Definition~\ref{def:architecture-axis-map}, passage or evidence on one architecture axis cannot certify a load-bearing claim whose claim kind requires another axis. More precisely, if a claim certificate uses an axis $A$ but its stronger reading needs an evidence item or negative-boundary discharge listed only on a different axis $A'$, then the stronger reading is not accepted unless the package contains a separate submitted coordinate for $A'$ and the gate
472|lemma|Manual bounded source-interface extraction correctness|lem:source-interface-extraction-correctness|For the pinned newmath repository path \path{papers/bedc/parts/visions/audit_map_methodology/automated_theory_discovery_pipeline_calculus.tex} at commit \path{3fb3d6a0641767388a401883062aa522ea0b397b}, Table~\ref{tab:source-interface-record} is the complete imported interface used by this paper at the manual path-verified level and only at that level. Its extraction certificate is: manual line-range audit against the pinned file, mirrored in \path{source_interface_record.json}, extraction date 2
511|proposition|Manual source-interface non-escalation|prop:manual-source-interface-non-escalation|Let $I$ be the imported discovery-gate interface certified by Lemma~\ref{lem:source-interface-extraction-correctness}. Any later use of an imported source label in this paper is a consequence of $I$ only if it is a function of the finite fields recorded in Table~\ref{tab:source-interface-record}: the source path, pinned commit, label, line range, extraction date, bounded summary, and evidence-level qualifier. A proposed stronger use---for example an exact import of the original source theorem st
554|proposition|Reviewable source-snapshot interface|prop:reviewable-source-snapshot-interface|The imported discovery-gate spine used in the finite-record interface theorem, Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}, has a reviewer-facing source interface. Namely, the tuple consisting of the pinned local source path, commit \path{3fb3d6a0641767388a401883062aa522ea0b397b}, Table~\ref{tab:source-interface-record}, \path{source_interface_record.json}, and the supplemental copy \path{review_bundle/source_snapshots/automated_theory_discovery_pipeline_calculus_3fb3d6a0641767388a401883062aa
584|proposition|Executable source-interface record comparison|prop:source-interface-record-file-consistency|The source-interface table, its JSON mirror, and the bundled source snapshot give one record-level imported discovery-gate interface for the finite-record interface theorem, Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}. The record fields are as follows: the source commit is \path{3fb3d6a0641767388a401883062aa522ea0b397b}; the bundled snapshot is \path{review_bundle/source_snapshots/automated_theory_discovery_pipeline_calculus_3fb3d6a0641767388a401883062aa522ea0b397b.tex}; the finite comparison
653|proposition|Source-interface evidence-level separation|prop:source-interface-evidence-level-separation|Let $r$ be any accepted manuscript claim whose discovery component cites one of the imported labels in Table~\ref{tab:source-interface-record}. If $r$ uses only Lemma~\ref{lem:source-interface-extraction-correctness}, then the imported-label premise of $r$ is accepted only at the manual path-verified bounded-paraphrase level. If $r$ additionally cites Proposition~\ref{prop:source-interface-record-file-consistency}, then the same premise is upgraded only by the finite record comparisons listed in
741|definition|Operational acceptance interface|def:operational-acceptance-interface|A \emph{claim} is a manuscript assertion that can affect a mathematical, artifact, route, or submission decision. A \emph{load-bearing claim} is a claim whose removal would change a theorem statement, a case-study conclusion, or the submission-readiness status. An \emph{advisory output} is any AI-agent draft, score, suggested theorem, review packet, or repair proposal before a gate records it. A \emph{deterministic gate} is a repeatable predicate, script, or checklist whose inputs and pass/fail 
922|definition|Record-gate soundness external interface|def:record-gate-soundness-external-interface|The external record-gate interface for a package is the finite predicate \[ \mathsf{RGS}_{S}(P,L,\Gamma) \] with the following inputs and outputs. Its inputs are exactly a package $P$, a submitted support surface $S$, a finite acceptance ledger $L$, and the deterministic claim-kind dispatch table $\Gamma$ of Definition~\ref{def:operational-acceptance-interface}. Its positive output is the finite family of certificates \[ \{\mathcal C(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B): c\in L \text{ is an accepted load-beari
954|proposition|Record-gate interface equivalence and non-claim boundary|prop:record-gate-soundness-external-interface-exactness|For the operational acceptance interface of Definition~\ref{def:operational-acceptance-interface}, the standalone interface in Definition~\ref{def:record-gate-soundness-external-interface} is equivalent to the predicate $\mathsf{RGS}_{S}(P,L,\Gamma)$ used in the publication-safety theorem. Moreover, under this interface every consequence used by Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface} is determined by the finite coordinates $(P,S,L,\Gamma)$ and by the displayed certificates $\mathcal C(c)
998|definition|Stronger-reading preorder|def:stronger-reading-preorder|Fix the dispatch table $\Gamma$ and certificate tuple $\mathcal C(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B)$ of Definition~\ref{def:operational-acceptance-interface}. A proposed reading $c^{+}$ of the same prose claim is \emph{record-stronger} than $c$, written $c\preceq_{\Gamma} c^{+}$, if at least one of the following finite coordinates is strictly enlarged while the others are unchanged or enlarged: the claim-kind set $K$; the evidence level, from $\mathsf{path}$ to $\mathsf{command}$; the evidence surface $E$; 
1022|definition|Certificate-schema acceptance table|def:certificate-schema-acceptance-table|Fix the seven-kind dispatch table $\Gamma$ of Definition~\ref{def:operational-acceptance-interface}. The verifier input for a load-bearing claim $c$ is the following finite record type: \[ \mathcal C(c)= \{K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B\}. \] Its typed fields are these and only these: $K$ is a finite set of claim kinds; $\ell\in\{\mathsf{path},\mathsf{command}\}$ is the declared evidence level; $E$ is a finite evidence-surface list; $H$ is the route-boundary field; $R$ is a finite family of gate pass records,
1062|proposition|Finite certificate schema verifier as a record check|prop:finite-certificate-schema-verifier|For every load-bearing manuscript claim $c$ whose component kinds lie in the seven-kind domain, $V(c,\mathcal C)$ is a finite, prose-insensitive record-schema verifier for the declared publication certificate. The submitted package instantiates $V$ by the script \path{review_bundle/verify_certificate_records.py}. On the positive package input it reads the schema file, pass-record ledger, submission-interface map, primary-claim inventory, and review-bundle manifest named above, and outputs accept
1128|theorem|Verifier input--predicate--output contract|thm:verifier-input-output-contract|The verifier interface used by the publication-safety theorem is exactly the following finite mathematical-software contract. Its input is a pair $(c,\mathcal C(c))$, where $c$ is a load-bearing manuscript claim and \(\mathcal C(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B)\) is the certificate record of Definition~\ref{def:certificate-schema-acceptance-table}, together with the fixed dispatch table $\Gamma$ and the submitted support surface $S$. Its checked predicates and outputs are: \centering \small {\linewidth}{p{
1195|theorem|Finite verifier normal form|thm:finite-verifier-normal-form|Fix the dispatch table $\Gamma$, the submitted support surface $S$, and the finite certificate schema of Definition~\ref{def:certificate-schema-acceptance-table}. There is a deterministic verifier \[ \mathsf{Check}_{\Gamma,S}(c,K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B) \] with the following presentation-layer input/output normal form. \small {\linewidth}{p{0.18\linewidth}p{0.36\linewidth}X} \toprule Step & Input fields read & Returned value \\ \midrule 1 & $K,\ell$ & reject with $(Q_1,K,\ell)$, or continue \\ 2 & $E$ a
1262|theorem|Schema-relative finite-record acceptance exactness|thm:record-acceptance-exactness|Fix the seven-kind dispatch table $\Gamma$, the two evidence levels, and the typed certificate tuple $\mathcal C(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B)$ of Definition~\ref{def:certificate-schema-acceptance-table}. For every load-bearing claim $c$ and every finite candidate certificate $\mathcal C(c)$, the finite verifier $V$ of Definition~\ref{def:operational-acceptance-interface} and Theorem~\ref{thm:verifier-input-output-contract} accepts $\mathcal C(c)$ if and only if the six-clause table predicate $\mathsf{A
1322|corollary|Executable schema exactness and negative fixture|cor:executable-schema-exactness-negative-fixture|Under the hypotheses and fixed schema of Theorem~\ref{thm:record-acceptance-exactness}, the executable verifier instance \path{review_bundle/verify_certificate_records.py} is a finite witness of the same schema-relative relation, not an additional semantic oracle. On the positive submitted package it can witness exactly the records satisfying \(\mathsf{Acc}_{\Gamma}\) at their declared evidence levels. On the negative fixture \path{review_bundle/negative_certificate_record_example.json}, which u
1361|theorem|Finite-coordinate determination and trust-boundary classifier|thm:finite-coordinate-determination-boundary|Fix the dispatch table $\Gamma$ and the verifier $V$. Let $F_{\Gamma}$ be the finite schema projection read by $V$ from a certificate record, namely the claim-kind set, declared evidence level, evidence surface, promotion field, gate-pass rows, discovery-source rows, command-boundary tuple, and the assigned gate set determined by $\Gamma$. If two ambient pipeline or artifact states induce the same values of all coordinates in $F_{\Gamma}$ for a claim $c$, then they induce the same record-accepta
1423|proposition|Machine-readable certificate records|prop:machine-readable-certificate-records|For the current presentation package, the finite record checker $V$ of Proposition~\ref{prop:finite-certificate-schema-verifier}, with the record-acceptance semantics of Theorem~\ref{thm:record-acceptance-exactness}, has an executable record-level instance over the review bundle, conditional on exact supplemental inclusion of \path{review_bundle/} in the completed submission with matching final digests, as stated in Proposition~\ref{audit:review-bundle-availability-condition}. The schema file \p
1525|theorem|Executable record non-escalation|thm:executable-record-non-escalation|Let $F$ be the finite field projection read by \path{review_bundle/verify_certificate_records.py}: manifest-field presence, entries $a_1$--$a_6$, claim-kind membership, evidence-level membership, assigned-gate coverage, pass-record fields, evidence-level agreement, discovery-field discipline, path-verified boundary status, row locks for \path{sim1}--\path{sim4}, and row-class locks for \path{pc1}--\path{pc12}. Assuming the exact-or-archive-equivalent review-bundle support surface of Proposition~
1583|theorem|Executable certificate-construction invariant|thm:executable-certificate-construction-invariant|For the submitted review bundle, let $G$ be the union of the finite fields read by the two executable verifiers \path{review_bundle/verify_source_interface_record.py} and \path{review_bundle/verify_certificate_records.py}. Thus $G$ contains the ten source-interface table triples, the JSON source-interface records, the pinned source snapshot path, digest, line count, declared source commit and line ranges, the six current-package pass-record entries $a_1,\ldots,a_6$, the submission-map rows \path
1651|proposition|Deterministic claim-kind dispatch|prop:claim-kind-dispatch|For every load-bearing manuscript claim whose kind lies in the seven-kind domain above, $\Gamma$ assigns a unique finite set of deterministic gates. In a pipeline that is record-gate-sound for acceptance, a mixed load-bearing claim may be used as accepted work only if its acceptance entry records passage through every gate in the union assigned to its component kinds.
1672|theorem|Mixed-claim projection obstruction|thm:mixed-claim-projection-obstruction|Let $c$ be a load-bearing mixed claim with nonempty component-kind set $K\subseteq\mathsf{Dom}(\Gamma)$ and submitted candidate certificate $\mathcal C(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B)$. For a nonempty subset $J\subseteq K$, write \[ G_J=\bigcup_{k\in J}\Gamma(k) \] and let $c_J$ denote the projected reading of $c$ that keeps exactly the claim-kind components in $J$ and keeps the same declared evidence level, evidence surface, promotion boundary, and command boundary, except that the discovery field is req
1735|theorem|Concrete finite-script projection soundness|thm:concrete-finite-script-implementation-soundness|Let $S$ be the submitted support surface containing \path{review_bundle/certificate_schema.json}, \path{review_bundle/current_package_pass_records.json}, \path{review_bundle/submission_interface_map.json}, \path{review_bundle/primary_claim_inventory.json}, \path{source_interface_record.json}, \path{review_bundle/REVIEW_BUNDLE_MANIFEST.json}, the bundled pinned source snapshot, and \path{theorem_inventory.json}. Let $\mathcal V$ be the four-script family consisting of \path{review_bundle/verify_c
1830|corollary|Finite-script projection instantiation boundary|cor:finite-script-rgs-instantiation-boundary|Assume the hypotheses of Theorem~\ref{thm:concrete-finite-script-implementation-soundness} and suppose the submitted command-run records for the four named scripts have exit code $0$. Then the only command-run coordinate instantiated for those scripts is the schema-level finite projection coordinate for the predicates printed by those scripts. Consequently Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface} may use those command-run rows to support schema-relative certificate coverage, source-interfa
1840|theorem|Assigned-gate soundness audit boundary|thm:assigned-gate-soundness-audit-boundary|Let $P$ be a finite submitted package with pass-record ledger $L$, dispatch table $\Gamma$, and submitted support surface $S$. For a load-bearing claim $c$, write $G(c)=\bigcup_{k\in K(c)}\Gamma(k)$ for the finite set of gates assigned to its claim-kind set. The package may use a ledger row for $c$ as a sound record-gate witness only through the finite predicate $\mathsf{RGS}_{S}(P,L,\Gamma)$ of Definition~\ref{def:operational-acceptance-interface}. Equivalently, the available finite-record stre
1909|theorem|Finite certificate obstruction skeleton|thm:finite-certificate-obstruction-skeleton|Let $c$ be a load-bearing manuscript claim whose component kinds lie in the seven-kind domain. The verifier of Proposition~\ref{prop:finite-certificate-schema-verifier} gives the following complete audit classification at the declared evidence level. A certificate for $c$ passes the publication-safety interface if and only if it has no bad subrecord of the following five types: \item missing evidence surface for the declared evidence level; \item missing pass record for a gate in $\bigcup_{k\in 
2010|theorem|Finite extension-budget normal form|thm:finite-extension-budget-normal-form|Fix the dispatch table $\Gamma$, the finite certificate schema, and an accepted finite certificate \(\mathcal C(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B)\) for a load-bearing package claim $c$. Let $c^{+}$ be a proposed stronger reading of the same row which is not record-equivalent to $c$ in the sense of Theorem~\ref{thm:finite-coordinate-determination-boundary}. Then $c^{+}$ is accepted by the publication-safety interface if and only if the submitted finite record surface contains an extension record in the follo
2097|proposition|Gate-interface separation|prop:gate-interface-separation|The promotion, overlap, submission-state, and theorem-content delta gates are separate deterministic interfaces. None can be replaced by passage of another one when a load-bearing claim has the corresponding component.
2121|corollary|Human promotion is not daemon-visible active-track equivalence|cor:human-promotion-daemon-active-track-separation|In the operational interface of Definition~\ref{def:operational-acceptance-interface}, a human-promotion record and daemon-visible active-paper markers are not interchangeable certificate fields. More precisely, let $c$ be any route-boundary claim whose accepted certificate is $\mathcal C(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B)$. The certificate may be read as saying that a candidate is admitted to the publication-facing package only when the promotion field $H$ records the human editorial act and the correspondi
2169|proposition|Scheduler selection is advisory before discovery gating|prop:scheduler-selection-advisory|Let $s$ be a scheduler or critical-path score attached to a candidate claim $c$. If $s$ recommends selecting $c$, then the recommendation is a work-selection claim and by itself can only pass the scheduler gate. If $c$ is also asserted to be a discovery or classifier-shifting contribution in a record-gate-sound pipeline, then the accepted mixed claim must pass both the scheduler gate and the discovery gate. Consequently, critical-path scores may prioritize review order, and the imported classifi
2244|proposition|Minimal bad-record witness for command-run escalation|prop:publication-safety-minimal-bad-record-witness|In the operational interface of Definition~\ref{def:operational-acceptance-interface}, let $r$ be a submitted claim record whose claim-kind set is \{route\}, whose evidence level is declared to be command-run, and whose boundary field contains no command-run tuple $(\text{command},\text{source state},\text{environment},\text{exit code}, \text{log path})$. Suppose all other route coordinates of $r$ are filled: there is an evidence pointer, a human-promotion marker at the declared boundary, and pa
2288|theorem|Conditional finite-record safety interface under record-gate soundness|thm:publication-safety-interface|Consider a theory-to-paper pipeline with the operational interface above and a finite submitted record surface consisting only of the manuscript source, printed tables, submitted manifests, uploaded review-bundle records, recorded logs, and explicitly declared historical boundaries. Assume the following four distinct finite-record hypotheses. \item \emph{Acceptance entries}: every load-bearing claim in an active manuscript is either rejected or has an acceptance entry with an evidence surface in
2480|theorem|Finite-record certificate rigidity|thm:finite-record-certificate-rigidity|Fix the finite submitted record surface $S$, acceptance ledger $L$, dispatch table $\Gamma$, and schema verifier $V$ used in Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}. Assume the same record-gate soundness and source-interface hypotheses as that theorem. For every accepted load-bearing claim $c$ with certificate \(\mathcal C(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B)\), the following are equivalent for a properly stronger reading $c^{+}$ in the preorder of Definition~\ref{def:stronger-reading-preorder}. \item T
2562|theorem|Boundary-axis exact non-escalation|thm:boundary-axis-non-escalation-exactness|Assume the hypotheses of Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}, and let \(c\) be any load-bearing claim accepted by the finite certificate constructed there. The following five stronger readings of \(c\), when they are not already record-equivalent to \(c\), are accepted by the same publication-safety interface if and only if the submitted finite support surface contains the indicated positive extension coordinates and the added coordinates pass the gates assigned by \(\Gamma\): \item A
2698|theorem|Mixed-interface overclaim skeleton|thm:mixed-interface-overclaim-skeleton|Assume the hypotheses of Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}. Let $c$ be an accepted load-bearing claim whose proof uses one or more of the following interface families: record-gate passage, bounded source-interface import, current-package ledger rows, manifest-bounded finite-witness rows, or theorem-obligation inventory rows. Let $c^{+}$ be a proposed reading obtained from $c$ by adding any finite nonempty set $J$ of stronger demands from the following five axes: \item \emph{gate imp
2804|theorem|Scoped boundary normal form for the presentation package|thm:presentation-scoped-boundary-normal-form|Assume the submitted package is evaluated only through the finite-record interface of Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}. Then every accepted load-bearing claim using one of the five interface components below has the stated maximal bounded reading, and every strictly stronger reading has the indicated unpaid obstruction unless the submitted surface is enlarged by a fresh finite coordinate and its assigned pass record. \item \emph{Publication safety}: the accepted reading is conditio
2918|theorem|Five-axis upgrade obstruction|thm:five-axis-upgrade-obstruction|Assume the hypotheses of Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}. Let $c$ be an accepted load-bearing claim in this presentation package whose proof uses at least one of the following bounded interfaces: \[ \text{record-gate},\quad \text{source-interface},\quad \text{finite-witness},\quad \text{primary-inventory},\quad \text{theorem-inventory}. \] For each such interface there is a finite upgrade coordinate \(U_j(c)\subseteq \Delta(c,c^{+})\) with the following exact form. \item For a rec
3024|theorem|Current boundary skeleton and non-gluing lower bound|thm:current-boundary-skeleton-non-gluing|Assume the support-surface hypotheses used by the current-package instantiation, including the six-row state $P^{+}_{6}$ of Theorem~\ref{thm:current-package-certificate-exactness}, the finite-script projection records of Theorem~\ref{thm:concrete-finite-script-implementation-soundness}, the manifest-bounded artifact coordinate $\mathcal M_{a_6}$ of Theorem~\ref{thm:finite-witness-manifest-record-interface}, and the syntactic theorem-environment domain $\mathcal E$ of Theorem~\ref{thm:determinist
3131|proposition|Certificate constructor and bad-subrecord extractor|prop:certificate-constructor-bad-subrecord-extractor|Assume the four finite-record hypotheses of Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}. For every ledger row \(c\) there is a deterministic partial constructor \[ \mathsf{Cert}_{\Gamma}(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B) \] and a deterministic extractor \(\mathsf{Bad}_{\Gamma}(c)\) with the following properties. \item \(\mathsf{Cert}_{\Gamma}(c)\) is defined and accepted if and only if the six-clause predicate \(\mathsf{Acc}_{\Gamma}(c,\mathsf{Cert}_{\Gamma}(c))\) holds. \item If \(\mathsf{Cert}_{\Gamma}
3195|proposition|Finite-record maximality|prop:publication-safety-maximality|Under the hypotheses of Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}, the constructed certificate is maximal with respect to the finite submitted record surface. More precisely, let $c$ be an accepted load-bearing claim and let $\mathsf{Cert}_{\Gamma}(c)=(K,\ell,E,H,R,D,B)$ be the certificate constructed in that theorem. If a stronger reading $c^{+}$ asserts any external end-to-end compiler correctness, current execution of unrecorded gates, proof-assistant correctness, current formal-source c
3237|corollary|Current-package source-level instance of the safety interface|cor:publication-safety-current-package-instance|For the current package, assume the support-surface condition later closed by Theorem~\ref{thm:final-support-surface-closure}: the exact supplemental \path{review_bundle/} directory is uploaded with the submission, or an archive-equivalent replacement with matching final digest records is supplied. Under that explicit availability condition, the finite pass-row components of the hypotheses of Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface} are witnessed by the machine-readable evidence map of Pro
3279|corollary|Finite-record boundary for external gate soundness|cor:finite-record-gate-soundness-boundary|Under the hypotheses of the finite-record interface theorem, Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}, the publication-safety conclusion is invariant under replacement of the surrounding implementation by any other implementation with the same submitted acceptance entries, evidence surfaces, promotion fields, discovery-interface rows, and evidence-level boundaries. Therefore the theorem cannot be used, without an additional submitted record-gate-soundness certificate, to infer external wor
3326|theorem|Boundary extension criterion for implementation-soundness readings|thm:implementation-soundness-extension-criterion|Fix the dispatch table $\Gamma$ and the finite certificate schema of Proposition~\ref{prop:finite-certificate-schema-verifier}. A reading of a load-bearing package claim as an implementation-soundness claim is accepted by the same publication-safety interface if and only if the submitted finite record surface is enlarged by an implementation-soundness extension record \[ \mathsf{Impl}(c)=(K^{\mathrm{impl}},E^{\mathrm{impl}},R^{\mathrm{impl}},B^{\mathrm{impl}}) \] with the following properties. \
3412|corollary|Submitted gate-implementation contract dichotomy|cor:submitted-gate-implementation-contract-dichotomy|Fix the package ledger $L$, support surface $S$, and dispatch table $\Gamma$ of the publication-safety interface. A claim that the actual gate-producing daemons or human workflow of the package satisfy record-gate soundness is accepted by the theorem chain of this paper only in the following submitted-form case: the package includes a finite implementation contract \[ \mathsf{GateImpl}(P)=(I,E_I,R_I,B_I) \] where $I$ names the gate-producing implementations and human boundary procedures, $E_I\su
3461|theorem|External-interface projection and no-free-implementation upgrade|thm:external-interface-projection-no-free-upgrade|Fix a package $P$, submitted surface $S$, acceptance ledger $L$, and dispatch table $\Gamma$. Let $\pi(P,S,L,\Gamma)$ be the finite record projection that retains only the fields read by the certificate schema: claim kinds, evidence levels, submitted evidence pointers, human-promotion fields, assigned passing gate rows, discovery-interface rows, and command-boundary tuples. Then the following are equivalent for the publication-safety conclusion of Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}. 
3561|proposition|Current-package acceptance and certificate ledger|prop:current-package-acceptance-certificate-ledger|Let $P^{+}$ be the finite current package consisting of the primary source \path{submission_abstract.tex}, this supplement \path{main.tex}, and, under the exact-or-archive-equivalent support-surface condition of Proposition~\ref{audit:review-bundle-availability-condition}, \path{review_bundle/REVIEW_BUNDLE_MANIFEST.json}, together with \path{review_bundle/certificate_schema.json}, \path{review_bundle/current_package_pass_records.json}, \path{review_bundle/submission_interface_map.json}, \path{re
3671|theorem|Current-package schema-relative finite-record certificate exactness|thm:current-package-certificate-exactness|For the six-row finite current-package state $P^{+}_{6}$ of Proposition~\ref{prop:current-package-acceptance-certificate-ledger}, assume the support-surface availability condition of Theorem~\ref{thm:final-support-surface-closure}: the submitted supplemental material contains the exact \path{review_bundle/} directory with \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md}, with refreshed digest rows and rerun finite-verifier logs for every named bundle coordinate regenerated after the digest surface w
3784|theorem|Ledger dependence and semantic extractor-completeness boundary|thm:manual-ledger-dependence-boundary|For the current package, the exactness assertions in Proposition~\ref{prop:current-package-acceptance-certificate-ledger}, Theorem~\ref{thm:current-package-certificate-exactness}, and Theorem~\ref{thm:theorem-obligation-ledger-boundary} are exactly finite-record claims over the displayed ledger rows, the submitted theorem-obligation inventory, and the syntactic theorem-environment extractor certificate of Theorem~\ref{thm:deterministic-theorem-environment-extractor-boundary}. They therefore impl
3863|corollary|Row-frozen current-package invariance|cor:row-frozen-current-package-invariance|Under the support-surface hypotheses of Theorem~\ref{thm:current-package-certificate-exactness}, the current-package acceptance decision factors through the six displayed rows \(a_1,\ldots,a_6\) and their certificate fields only. Any two ambient repository, daemon, artifact, or venue states that induce the same six tuples \(\mathcal C(a_i)=(K_i,\ell_i,E_i,H_i,R_i,D_i,B_i)\), the same submitted support surface, and the same verifier log path induce the same accepted current-package certificate se
3905|theorem|Current-package extension-coordinate rigidity|thm:current-package-extension-coordinate-rigidity|Assume the support-surface hypotheses of Theorem~\ref{thm:current-package-certificate-exactness}. Let \(P^{+}_{6}\) be the accepted six-row current-package state and let \(F_{6}\) be its finite schema projection: the row identifiers \(a_1,\ldots,a_6\), their tuples \(\mathcal C(a_i)=(K_i,\ell_i,E_i,H_i,R_i,D_i,B_i)\), the submitted support surface, the fixed dispatch table, and the recorded verifier log. Then \(F_{6}\) is the largest current-package invariant certified by this submission before 
3998|theorem|Current-package semantic non-escalation|thm:current-package-semantic-non-escalation|Let $P^{+}_{6}$ be the six-row current-package state of Theorem~\ref{thm:current-package-certificate-exactness}, and assume the same support-surface availability condition. For each accepted row $a_i$ with certificate \(\mathcal C(a_i)=(K_i,\ell_i,E_i,H_i,R_i,D_i,B_i)\), the following are equivalent for any proposed stronger reading $a_i^{+}$ of the same manuscript row. \item $a_i^{+}$ is accepted by the finite-record safety interface for the current package. \item The package supplies a positiv
4064|theorem|Named boundary positive-coordinate classification|thm:named-boundary-positive-coordinate-classification|Assume the support-surface hypotheses of Theorem~\ref{thm:current-package-certificate-exactness}. Let $F_{6}$ be the finite six-row projection of Theorem~\ref{thm:current-package-extension-coordinate-rigidity}. Consider a proposed strengthened reading of one of the following six boundary interfaces: \item reading Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface} as end-to-end correctness of the AI-assisted workflow rather than conditional finite-record non-escalation; \item reading Theorem~\ref{thm
4174|corollary|Current package path-verified instantiation|cor:current-package-path-verified-instantiation|For the current presentation package, let $P$ be the finite package consisting of the primary source \path{submission_abstract.tex}, this supplement \path{main.tex}, and the exact-or-archive-equivalent review-bundle support surface of Proposition~\ref{audit:review-bundle-availability-condition}, together with the executable certificate records named in Proposition~\ref{prop:machine-readable-certificate-records}. Root-level workflow diagnostic files are local historical/path-verified context only
4277|lemma|Gate-witness criterion|lem:gate-witness-criterion|A case record is a historical path-verified witness for the safety interface when it names the source or artifact snapshot surface, the invariant that failed, the gate decision recorded for that snapshot, and the safe manuscript lesson. Under the finite-record interface theorem, Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}, such a witness can support a case-study claim about the recorded historical gate surface, but not a stronger command-run, benchmark, live-daemon, rebuild, dynamic-artifact,
4302|proposition|Path-complete case witnesses|prop:path-complete-case-witnesses|Suppose a case-study row is used as load-bearing evidence for the finite-record interface theorem, Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}. If the row is path-complete in the sense above, then the row supplies exactly the evidence surface required for a path-verified historical snapshot case claim and no evidence surface for a fresh daemon, full-source, theorem-content, artifact-suite, benchmark, or semantic-substrate rerun. In fact every accepted path-complete case row factors through on
4430|proposition|Review-bundle case-snapshot coverage|prop:review-bundle-case-snapshot-coverage|For the four case-study rows in Table~\ref{tab:case-witnesses}, the review bundle contains a finite external-review surface for every local case path used by the paper. The Newmath block has two local paths, the upper-fibers block has five local paths, the fake-extension block has two local paths, and the Rule110 block has four local paths, for thirteen local-path strings after resolving this paper's relative \path{ARTIFACT_INVENTORY.md} to its absolute path in the paper directory. The manifest 
4489|theorem|Case-witness skeleton rigidity|thm:case-witness-skeleton-rigidity|Let \(r\) be one of the four case-study rows in Table~\ref{tab:case-witnesses}, and assume the path-completeness and review-bundle coverage conclusions of Propositions~\ref{prop:path-complete-case-witnesses} and \ref{prop:review-bundle-case-snapshot-coverage}. Then the accepted information carried by \(r\) is exactly one of the following four skeleton lessons and no other reproducibility or semantic-validation lesson: \item a promotion skeleton: an intake packet is not daemon-visible publication
4632|proposition|Fresh venue-record criterion|audit:fresh-venue-record-criterion|Assume that the final submitted support surface contains either the venue-check record \path{VENUE_CHECK.md} and log \path{VENUE_CHECK_RUN_2026-06-04.log}, the later local-date rerun log \path{review_bundle/VENUE_BIBLIOGRAPHY_LIVE_CHECK_2026-06-07.log}, or an archive-equivalent replacement naming the same checked URLs, observation time, route rules, command result, source state, environment, exit code, and log path. Then the venue row of Proposition~\ref{audit:venue-submission-pack-gate} is acce
4673|theorem|Venue-rule freshness non-escalation|thm:venue-rule-freshness-non-escalation|Let $U$ be the finite dated venue record consisting of the official call URL, the submission-form URL, the style-guideline URL, the observation date and time, the HTTP-status run witness \path{VENUE_CHECK_RUN_2026-06-04.log} or the later rerun witness \path{review_bundle/VENUE_BIBLIOGRAPHY_LIVE_CHECK_2026-06-07.log}, the observed route class, page limit, proceedings boundary, deadline, supplement access rule, and the local witness rows in Table~\ref{tab:venue-submission-pack-gate}. The venue com
4715|corollary|Historical venue record non-escalation|cor:historical-venue-record-non-escalation|The venue check recorded at \path{VENUE_CHECK_RUN_2026-06-04.log}, with local observation time \path{2026-06-04 10:15 Asia/Singapore}, is a historical venue record. For the present post-2026-06-04 source state it is superseded, for local readiness only, by the rerun log \path{review_bundle/VENUE_BIBLIOGRAPHY_LIVE_CHECK_2026-06-07.log}, whose local observation time is \path{2026-06-07 01:22:24 Asia/Singapore} and whose exit code is \path{0}. Neither dated record certifies actual upload-time EasyC
4744|corollary|Upload-time venue-compliance record requirement|cor:upload-time-venue-compliance-record-requirement|The logs \path{VENUE_CHECK_RUN_2026-06-04.log} and \path{review_bundle/VENUE_BIBLIOGRAPHY_LIVE_CHECK_2026-06-07.log} are dated local-readiness records. For the current package they certify only the venue rule state observed at their recorded observation times. The current source package contains no EasyChair upload receipt, no completed-upload timestamp, and no finite statement tying a completed upload to the unchanged venue-rule state; the public branch/path archive-equivalent locator is a supp
4793|proposition|Round-five venue-record instantiation|prop:round-five-venue-record-instantiation|The file \path{review_bundle/VENUE_BIBLIOGRAPHY_LIVE_CHECK_2026-06-07.log} instantiates the dated local-readiness branch required by Corollary~\ref{cor:upload-time-venue-compliance-record-requirement}. Its finite fields are the command \path{PowerShell Invoke-WebRequest against CICM route pages and bibliography authority pages}, environment \path{Windows PowerShell 5.1 from paper directory; network enabled}, source state \path{current working tree for main.tex, submission_abstract.tex, reference
4842|proposition|Venue-submission pack gate|audit:venue-submission-pack-gate|Assume only the dated venue-rule records currently named in this source package, with no upload receipt, no completed-upload timestamp, no archive-equivalent locator, and no unchanged-rule statement for a completed upload. Then the current package is submission-pack ready for this route only as a local pre-upload checklist exactly when the finite gate in Table~\ref{tab:venue-submission-pack-gate} passes: the primary artifact is the two-page-plus-bibliography source \path{submission_abstract.tex}
4913|proposition|Submission artifact role separation|audit:submission-artifact-role-separation|For the current presentation-only route, the primary artifact, long technical supplement, and review bundle have distinct review roles. The primary source \path{submission_abstract.tex} states the presentation claim, \path{main.tex} proves the long-form interface theorems and records the case tables, and \path{review_bundle/} supplies the supplemental source snapshots, case snapshots, and machine-readable manifest rows. None of these roles converts the support bundle into a second primary submis
5005|proposition|Formal-source gate instantiation|prop:formal-source-gate-instantiation|For the current presentation package, the Lean-facing assertions in rows \path{pc3} and \path{pc4} of Table~\ref{tab:primary-claim-inventory} are accepted only as bounded contextual interfaces, not as accepted formal-source claims. The accepted certificate surface is the traceability row $a_1$, the fake-extension boundary row $a_5$, Table~\ref{tab:source-interface-record}, \path{source_interface_record.json}, \path{review_bundle/primary_claim_inventory.json}, and \path{review_bundle/certificate_
5072|theorem|Formal-source promotion obstruction|thm:formal-source-promotion-obstruction|In the current presentation package, no manuscript sentence about the Lean/BEDC source interface can be promoted from bounded contextual interface evidence to an accepted formal-source claim unless the certificate is enlarged by an accepted formal-source row containing build-gate and axiom-purity-gate pass records. If a fresh execution reading is also asserted, the certificate must additionally contain the command, source commit or final package digest manifest, environment, exit code, and log p
5113|theorem|Evidence-level overclaim obstruction|thm:evidence-level-overclaim-obstruction|Fix the certificate schema, dispatch function, and evidence-level vocabulary of this paper. Let $c$ be a load-bearing claim whose accepted certificate has level path-verified and whose boundary field $B$ records that no command-run assertion is made. Then every stronger reading of $c$ that asserts any of the following additional conclusions is rejected by the finite schema verifier: \item external gate soundness for an arbitrary implementation of the workflow; \item Lean correctness, full-source
5188|theorem|Finite-witness manifest-bounded record interface|thm:finite-witness-manifest-record-interface|This theorem is a manifest-bounded finite-record interface instance of Theorem~\ref{thm:evidence-level-overclaim-obstruction}: it records only the bounded manifest/evaluator coordinates that may be checked, and it rejects stronger artifact readings unless the package supplies the additional finite records required for them, such as semantic-validation pass records or fresh rerun logs. The interface domain is the finite set \[ \mathcal M_{a_6}=\{\text{manifest entry},\text{local paths}, \text{rev
5308|corollary|Artifact semantic-validity boundary for finite witnesses|cor:artifact-semantic-validity-boundary|Let $c$ be a finite-witness artifact claim in the current package whose accepted certificate uses the artifact row $a_6$, and let $\mathcal M_{a_6}$ be the manifest-bounded coordinate set of Theorem~\ref{thm:finite-witness-manifest-record-interface}. If a proposed stronger reading $c^{\mathrm{sem}}$ asserts semantic validity of the unbounded Rule110/GroundCompiler artifact, semantic correctness of a dynamic evaluator, or artifact validity beyond the exact evaluator contract recorded in $\mathcal
5371|proposition|Primary-claim conditional inventory-audit classification|prop:primary-claim-row-classification|Assume the current primary source \path{submission_abstract.tex} is the submitted primary artifact, the twelve-row inventory \path{review_bundle/primary_claim_inventory.json} is supplied with the review bundle or an accepted archive-equivalent support surface, and the finite manual inventory audit has identified \path{pc1},\ldots,\path{pc12} as the load-bearing primary assertions. Then the current primary-claim inventory is complete for the short presentation note in the following conditional in
5436|proposition|Primary-inventory freshness criterion|prop:primary-inventory-freshness-criterion|Let $S$ be a later edited version of \path{submission_abstract.tex}, and let $I$ be a primary-claim inventory with rows of the same form as \path{review_bundle/primary_claim_inventory.json}: each row gives a location in $S$, a claim text or bounded paraphrase, a row status, a certificate surface, and an evidence level. Suppose a manual claim audit of $S$ produces a finite list of load-bearing assertions and verifies the following three conditions: \item every load-bearing assertion in $S$ appear
5508|proposition|Primary--supplement interface map|prop:primary-supplement-interface-map|Every load-bearing claim made in the current primary artifact \path{submission_abstract.tex} is certified by an explicit supplement theorem, table row, or manifest row at a declared evidence level. The certification map is Table~\ref{tab:submission-interface-map}, refined by Table~\ref{tab:primary-claim-inventory}, and mirrored in the \path{submission_interface_map} field of \path{review_bundle/REVIEW_BUNDLE_MANIFEST.json} and the file \path{review_bundle/submission_interface_map.json}. Therefor
5756|theorem|Exact-inclusion support-surface realization|thm:exact-inclusion-support-surface-realization|For the current package the selected support branch is exact supplemental inclusion of \path{review_bundle/}, but this branch remains conditional until an external upload-or-archive instantiation record exists. If the completed submission contains that directory with the certificate-file digests listed in \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md}, then every bundle-backed claim in this supplement has a submitted finite support surface at its stated path-verified evidence level. If the exact d
5794|theorem|Public branch archive-equivalent locator realization|thm:public-branch-archive-equivalent-realization|Let $L$ be the public automath branch/path coordinate recorded in \path{review_bundle/REVIEW_BUNDLE_MANIFEST.json} and in \cite{auditable-pipeline-review-bundle}. If $L$ contains \path{theorem_inventory.json}, \path{theorem_inventory.md}, and the regular files under \path{review_bundle/} with the same relative paths and the SHA--256 rows printed in \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md}, then $L$ is an archive-equivalent support surface for every bundle-backed and theorem-inventory claim i
5840|corollary|Submission-time support instantiation test|cor:submission-time-support-instantiation-test|For a completed presentation-only submission, the bundle-backed and venue/bibliography-backed claims in this package instantiate external support if and only if the submitted support surface contains one of the following finite normal forms: \item exact inclusion of \path{theorem_inventory.json}, \path{theorem_inventory.md}, and \path{review_bundle/}, with \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md} regenerated after the inventory, extractor, verifier, primary-claim-freshness, and venue/bibliog
5894|theorem|Final support-surface closure|thm:final-support-surface-closure|For the current package, using Proposition~\ref{prop:final-package-shape-convention}, Audit record~\ref{prop:exact-review-bundle-upload-witness}, and Theorem~\ref{thm:exact-inclusion-support-surface-realization}, the bundle-backed claims in this supplement are admissible at the stated path-verified evidence level exactly when the submitted supplemental material contains the exact directory \path{review_bundle/} whose final packaging record is \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md}. The exa
6016|theorem|Workspace-to-final-package reconciliation|thm:workspace-final-package-reconciliation|Let $D_0$ be the digest manifest \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md}, and let $H_i$ denote the source state printed in verifier log $i$. The source-state claim made in Audit record~\ref{prop:final-immutable-package-state-certificate} is the finite package claim consisting of these recorded pairs $(H_i,D_0)$, not a claim that every later reviewer checkout, editor workspace, or post-packaging working tree has Git \path{HEAD} equal to a single historical commit. If a current workspace repo
6109|theorem|Support-surface normal form for bundle-backed claims|thm:support-surface-normal-form|For the current presentation package, every accepted use of a bundle-backed certificate coordinate is in exactly one of the following normal forms. \item \emph{Exact inclusion}: an external upload or submission receipt records that the submitted support surface contains the exact \path{review_bundle/} directory whose certificate-file bytes match \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md}. \item \emph{Archive-equivalent inclusion}: a replacement archive satisfies every row of Table~\ref{tab:rev
6176|theorem|Support-surface invariant compression|thm:support-surface-invariant-compression|Let $\mathcal S$ be the family of support-surface and post-inventory claims in Theorems~\ref{thm:final-support-surface-closure}, \ref{thm:workspace-final-package-reconciliation}, \ref{thm:support-surface-normal-form}, and \ref{thm:post-inventory-package-fixed-point}, together with Corollary~\ref{cor:stable-replay-post-inventory-tuple}. For the current package, every member of $\mathcal S$ is a projection of the same finite support tuple \[ \Sigma=(F,M,D,R,Q), \] where $F$ is the selected relativ
6241|theorem|Upload instantiation boundary|thm:upload-or-archive-instantiation-boundary|Before the bundle-backed claims of this supplement are treated as part of a completed venue submission, the external submission record must instantiate the support-surface branch selected by Proposition~\ref{prop:final-package-shape-convention} and Theorems~\ref{thm:final-support-surface-closure} and \ref{thm:support-surface-normal-form}: it must record that \path{review_bundle/} was uploaded exactly with digest manifest $D_0$ and with the root \path{theorem_inventory.json} coordinate named by t
6279|corollary|Upload-or-archive instantiation record|cor:upload-or-archive-instantiation-record|The bundle-backed support claims of the current package may be used only under the external-record condition of Theorem~\ref{thm:upload-or-archive-instantiation-boundary}. In particular, \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md} is a local byte-level packaging manifest and not, by itself, an upload receipt, DOI, or proof that the public branch/path locator already contains the matching bytes.
6294|proposition|No external instantiation from local bundle records|prop:no-external-instantiation-from-local-bundle-records|In the current source package, the rows of \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md}, the manifest fields of \path{review_bundle/REVIEW_BUNDLE_MANIFEST.json}, the bibliography entries \cite{automath-publication-pipeline,auditable-pipeline-review-bundle}, and the support notes in this supplement instantiate only a local exact-inclusion support mode and name the public branch/path archive-equivalent coordinate. They do not by themselves instantiate either admissible external-support branch of C
6338|proposition|Upload-or-archive instantiation update protocol|prop:upload-or-archive-instantiation-update-protocol|Suppose a later venue upload receipt or archive-equivalent locator is to be used to replace the current no-receipt boundary of Corollary~\ref{cor:upload-or-archive-instantiation-record} by an externally instantiated submitted-support claim. Then the replacement is accepted by the finite-record interface if and only if one of the two following finite update protocols is performed. The manuscript surfaces in the statement are precisely \path{submission_abstract.tex} and \path{main.tex}; the manife
6429|corollary|Current no-receipt support-surface non-escalation|cor:current-no-receipt-support-surface-non-escalation|In the current source package the records \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md}, \path{review_bundle/REVIEW_BUNDLE_MANIFEST.json}, \path{review_bundle/current_package_pass_records.json}, and \path{theorem_inventory.json} contain no venue upload receipt, public DOI, or institutional archive identifier for \path{review_bundle/}. They do record the public automath branch/path coordinate as an archive-equivalent locator, but only under matching file-list, digest, manifest, and path-semantics 
6482|corollary|Fresh inventory digest instance for this source state|cor:fresh-inventory-digest-instance-this-source-state|In the present source state, the regenerated files \path{theorem_inventory.json} and \path{theorem_inventory.md} are closed as local exact-inclusion coordinates only after their SHA-256 rows in \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md} are recomputed from the bytes of those two files and the finite command-boundary table names that refreshed manifest state. This corollary supplies no upload receipt, archive locator, extractor-completeness certificate, or semantic proof check; it supplies only
6514|theorem|Digest-closure refresh criterion for final package claims|thm:digest-closure-refresh-criterion|For the current presentation package, any claim that a submitted support surface has exact final digests is accepted only for a closed finite state $D$ satisfying all of the following conditions. \item The digest manifest \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md} contains SHA-256 rows for \path{main.tex}, \path{submission_abstract.tex}, \path{references.bib}, \path{source_interface_record.json}, \path{theorem_inventory.json}, \path{theorem_inventory.md}, and every file in the selected \path{r
6583|proposition|Primary architectural fallback without external support|prop:primary-architectural-fallback-without-external-support|Assume the current source package is used without an upload receipt for the exact \path{review_bundle/} directory and without an archive-equivalent replacement satisfying Audit record~\ref{audit:review-bundle-archive-equivalence}. Then the primary presentation article may assert only the source-level architecture and path-verified local-package claims whose evidence surfaces are visible outside the missing bundle. In particular, the theorem-ledger claim of Theorem~\ref{thm:theorem-obligation-led
6649|theorem|Deterministic theorem-environment extractor boundary|thm:deterministic-theorem-environment-extractor-boundary|Let the theorem-like environment domain $\mathcal E$ for this package consist of the five environment names \path{definition}, \path{lemma}, \path{proposition}, \path{theorem}, and \path{corollary}. The command \path{python review_bundle/extract_theorem_environments.py} run on \path{main.tex} and \path{theorem_inventory.json} is a deterministic syntactic extractor for the following finite claim only: every labelled environment in \path{main.tex} whose environment name belongs to $\mathcal E$ is 
6696|theorem|Theorem-inventory boundary|prop:manual-theorem-inventory-boundary|This theorem retains the legacy cross-reference label \path{prop:manual-theorem-inventory-boundary} for compatibility with earlier acceptance-ledger entries; its environment category is \path{theorem}, not \path{proposition}. The file \path{theorem_inventory.json} is a theorem-obligation inventory record whose current support has two finite parts. First, it is an obligation ledger selected by finite-record review and connected to the manifest and acceptance ledger. Second, Theorem~\ref{thm:deter
6748|proposition|Regenerated theorem-inventory digest closure|prop:regenerated-theorem-inventory-digest-closure|Suppose a theorem-inventory pass regenerates either \path{theorem_inventory.json} or \path{theorem_inventory.md} after the package has selected the exact-inclusion support branch. Then the final support-surface claims of Theorem~\ref{thm:final-support-surface-closure}, the submitted theorem-ledger claim of Theorem~\ref{thm:theorem-obligation-ledger-boundary}, and the command boundary of Proposition~\ref{audit:command-run-boundary-inventory} remain closed only under the fixed-point conditions of 
6797|corollary|Current theorem-inventory digest instance|cor:current-theorem-inventory-digest-instance|For the present local support package, after \path{theorem_inventory.json} and \path{theorem_inventory.md} have been regenerated, the submitted theorem-obligation ledger may be cited in Theorem~\ref{thm:theorem-obligation-ledger-boundary} only through the refreshed digest rows for those two files in \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md} and through fresh finite-record verifier logs produced after the regenerated inventory files are present. If either the two digest rows or the post-regene
6833|proposition|Post-inventory fixed-point support certificate|prop:post-inventory-fixed-point-support-certificate|In the present package state, the two regenerated theorem-inventory files are accepted by the exact-inclusion theorem-ledger chain only at the following finite fixed point: the rows of \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md} name \path{theorem_inventory.json} and \path{theorem_inventory.md}; the same digest manifest names the refreshed logs \path{review_bundle/certificate_verification_run.log}, \path{review_bundle/source_interface_verification_run.log}, \path{review_bundle/primary_claim_inv
6890|theorem|Post-inventory finite-record realization|thm:post-inventory-finite-record-realization|Suppose the following finite records are present in the current source package: \item \path{theorem_inventory.json} and \path{theorem_inventory.md}; \item a zero-exit log for \path{python review_bundle/extract_theorem_environments.py} computed after those two files were written; \item zero-exit logs for \path{python review_bundle/verify_certificate_records.py}, \path{python review_bundle/verify_source_interface_record.py}, and \path{python review_bundle/verify_primary_claim_inventory.py} compute
6955|theorem|Seven-row submitted theorem-obligation ledger integration|thm:theorem-obligation-ledger-boundary|Let $P^{+}_{7}$ be the seven-row support state obtained from $P^{+}_{6}$ by the conservative finite-record extension of Theorem~\ref{thm:nested-package-states}, namely by adding exactly the submitted theorem-ledger coordinate \path{a7}. In $P^{+}_{7}$, the theorem-obligation ledger is no longer a detached review-only artifact: the submitted finite support surface contains \path{theorem_inventory.json} through the manifest field \path{theorem_inventory} and through acceptance-ledger entry \path{a
7027|proposition|Post-inventory support-tuple extraction certificate|prop:post-inventory-support-tuple-extraction-certificate|For the current source package, the theorem-ledger support tuple is accepted only in the post-inventory form consisting of \path{theorem_inventory.json}, \path{theorem_inventory.md}, \path{review_bundle/theorem_environment_extraction_run.log}, \path{review_bundle/current_package_pass_records.json}, and \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md}. In that form the extraction log must be generated after the two inventory files exist, the pass-record ledger must contain the theorem-ledger certific
7069|proposition|Submitted theorem-inventory availability|prop:submitted-theorem-inventory-availability|If the external support-surface condition of Corollary~\ref{cor:upload-or-archive-instantiation-record} is satisfied, then \path{theorem_inventory.json} is an available submitted certificate coordinate for the bounded theorem-obligation ledger claim of Theorem~\ref{thm:theorem-obligation-ledger-boundary}. If the exact bundle is not uploaded with matching final digests, the theorem inventory has only local diagnostic force and cannot support a submitted theorem-ledger claim in the current package
7095|proposition|Submission-support instantiation field normal form|prop:submission-support-instantiation-field-normal-form|For the current source package, the upload-or-archive support coordinate has the following complete finite field normal form: \small {\textwidth}{p{0.29\textwidth}X} \toprule field & current value\\ \midrule support branch & conditional exact supplemental inclusion of \path{theorem_inventory.json}, \path{theorem_inventory.md}, and \path{review_bundle/}\\ upload receipt & absent\\ archive-equivalent locator & public automath branch/path coordinate, digest-conditioned\\ accepted external support s
7147|corollary|Current local-support normal form|cor:current-local-support-normal-form|For the current presentation package, the finite support state has exactly the following normal form. The theorem-inventory coordinate is accepted only through the post-regeneration digest-and-verifier fixed point of Proposition~\ref{prop:post-inventory-fixed-point-support-certificate}; the review-bundle coordinate is externally instantiated only under exact upload or matching public branch/path bytes, because Proposition~\ref{prop:submission-support-instantiation-field-normal-form} records no u
7202|proposition|Review-bundle availability condition|audit:review-bundle-availability-condition|The final support mode selected for the current presentation package is exact supplemental inclusion of \path{review_bundle/}, conditional on the external instantiation record of Corollary~\ref{cor:upload-or-archive-instantiation-record}, as recorded in \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md} and in Audit record~\ref{prop:final-immutable-package-state-certificate}. This is a conditional support-mode selection, not a completed venue-upload record or public archive locator. The source-interfa
7256|proposition|Case-snapshot non-rerun boundary|audit:case-snapshot-non-rerun-boundary|Under the hypotheses of Propositions~\ref{prop:path-complete-case-witnesses} and \ref{prop:review-bundle-case-snapshot-coverage}, the four case-study rows cannot be read as fresh dynamic-behavior claims. Any stronger reading asserting a fresh publication-daemon execution, full-source rebuild, theorem-content rerun, Rule110 dynamic rerun, or GroundCompiler semantic rerun requires command, source state, environment, exit-code, and log-path fields in addition to the bundled snapshots. Without those
7287|theorem|Finite-row closure of case evidence|thm:finite-row-case-evidence-closure|Let $C$ be the finite set of four case-study rows in Table~\ref{tab:case-witnesses}. Under Propositions~\ref{prop:path-complete-case-witnesses} and \ref{prop:review-bundle-case-snapshot-coverage}, the publication-safety interface accepts the case-study contribution exactly as the image of $C$ under the skeleton map of Theorem~\ref{thm:case-witness-skeleton-rigidity}. The image has four possible values only: promotion, route/submission blocking, theorem-content non-growth, and artifact-limitation
7382|proposition|Command-run boundary inventory|audit:command-run-boundary-inventory|For the current presentation package, Table~\ref{tab:command-boundary-inventory} is complete for the command-boundary claims used by Proposition~\ref{prop:machine-readable-certificate-records}, Proposition~\ref{audit:review-bundle-availability-condition}, and the finite-record interface theorem, Theorem~\ref{thm:publication-safety-interface}. The accepted command-boundary claims in the package are exactly the three refreshed finite record-verifier invocations recorded in \path{review_bundle/cert
7464|proposition|Final local support-state reconciliation|prop:final-local-support-state-reconciliation|For the current source package, the finite support state used by the publication-safety theorem chain is the following reconciled local state and no stronger one. First, the regenerated files \path{theorem_inventory.json} and \path{theorem_inventory.md} are accepted only through the refreshed SHA-256 rows in \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md} and through the finite verifier logs named in Proposition~\ref{prop:post-inventory-fixed-point-support-certificate}. Second, each command-run sou
7509|theorem|Submission-support fixed-point normal form|thm:submission-support-fixed-point-normal-form|For the current source package, the support state for the three externalized claims in the publication-safety theorem chain is exactly the following finite normal form. \item The theorem-inventory coordinate is accepted only after \path{theorem_inventory.json} and \path{theorem_inventory.md} have been written, the theorem-environment extractor and finite-record verifiers have been rerun on that post-inventory state, and \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md} has been regenerated over those
7570|theorem|Post-inventory support-coordinate dichotomy|thm:post-inventory-support-coordinate-dichotomy|For the current presentation package there are exactly two possible support readings for any claim whose evidence surface names \path{theorem_inventory.json}, \path{theorem_inventory.md}, or a file under \path{review_bundle/}. If the ordered post-inventory pass of Theorem~\ref{thm:post-inventory-package-fixed-point} has been run and the exact resulting surface is externally instantiated by the upload-or-archive record of Corollary~\ref{cor:upload-or-archive-instantiation-record}, then the claim 
7626|proposition|Final refreshed-coordinate instantiation|prop:final-refreshed-coordinate-instantiation|For the current dated local-readiness package, the first coordinate of Theorem~\ref{thm:submission-support-fixed-point-normal-form} is instantiated by the finite tuple consisting of \path{theorem_inventory.json}, \path{theorem_inventory.md}, \path{review_bundle/theorem_environment_extraction_run.log}, \path{review_bundle/certificate_verification_run.log}, \path{review_bundle/source_interface_verification_run.log}, \path{review_bundle/primary_claim_inventory_freshness_2026-06-07.log}, \path{revie
7672|theorem|Post-inventory package fixed point|thm:post-inventory-package-fixed-point|Let $P$ be the current local package state consisting of the manuscript source, \path{submission_abstract.tex}, \path{theorem_inventory.json}, \path{theorem_inventory.md}, and \path{review_bundle/}. Suppose that the following finite sequence is executed in the displayed order: \item write the theorem-inventory files for the manuscript source state; \item rerun \path{python review_bundle/extract_theorem_environments.py}; \item rerun the finite-record verifiers named in Table~\ref{tab:command-boun
7755|corollary|Round-two post-inventory realization|cor:round-two-post-inventory-realization|Assume that the present round-two source state contains the two submitted inventory files \path{theorem_inventory.json} and \path{theorem_inventory.md}. If, after those two files exist, the theorem-environment extractor, the retained finite-record verifiers, the retained dated venue/bibliography check, and the final SHA--256 manifest are run in the order displayed in Theorem~\ref{thm:post-inventory-package-fixed-point}, then the theorem-ledger row $a_7$ of Table~\ref{tab:current-acceptance-ledge
7792|theorem|Round-four inventory artifact realization|thm:round-four-inventory-artifact-realization|For the present Stage--A round-four source state, suppose that the files \path{theorem_inventory.json} and \path{theorem_inventory.md} are present as finite package coordinates and that, after those bytes exist, the following records are freshly regenerated from the same source state: the syntactic theorem-environment extraction log \path{review_bundle/theorem_environment_extraction_run.log}, the finite certificate verifier log \path{review_bundle/certificate_verification_run.log}, the source-in
7846|corollary|Current post-inventory support tuple instantiation|cor:current-post-inventory-support-tuple-instantiation|In the current source package, after \path{theorem_inventory.json} and \path{theorem_inventory.md} have been written, the ordered tuple consisting of \path{theorem_inventory.json}, \path{theorem_inventory.md}, \path{review_bundle/theorem_environment_extraction_run.log}, \path{review_bundle/certificate_verification_run.log}, \path{review_bundle/source_interface_verification_run.log}, \path{review_bundle/primary_claim_inventory_freshness_2026-06-07.log}, and \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA25
7893|corollary|Stable replay criterion for the post-inventory tuple|cor:stable-replay-post-inventory-tuple|Let $S$ be a source state of the present presentation package in which \path{theorem_inventory.json} and \path{theorem_inventory.md} exist. Suppose that the theorem-environment extractor, certificate-record verifier, source-interface verifier, and retained primary-claim verifier are run from $S$, that their logs have exit code zero, and that \path{review_bundle/FINAL_DIGESTS_SHA256.md} is regenerated after those logs are written. Then every later support claim for the first coordinate of Theorem
